COLLEGE
カレッジ
this is a test
これはテストです
Our topic today is
今日のトピックは
I'll see later
後で見てみましょう
It's Taipei Metropolis vs. Pompeii
台北メトロポリス対ポンペイです
Then we invited to this court
それから私たちはこの法廷に招待しました
Researcher Lin Zhengxiong of the Institute of Earth Sciences
地球科学研究所の林正雄研究員
Come give us a special presentation
特別なプレゼンテーションをしに来てください
I think everyone has heard of Pompeii
ポンペイについては誰もが聞いたことがあると思います
its an ancient city in italy
イタリアの古代都市です
more than 2000 years ago
2000年前
because of a volcanic eruption
火山の噴火のため
So it was a very prosperous ancient city
とても栄えた古代都市でした
It's gone all night
一晩中消えてしまった
Then we associate it with Taipei
それから台北を連想します
It’s because it’s actually next to Taipei City
実は台北市の隣だから
there is a volcano
火山があります
This is our special presentation today
今日は特別なプレゼンテーションです
I'm here to tell you about this
このことについてお話しするためにここに来ました
Our Datun Mountain is actually a volcano
私たちの大屯山は実は火山です
so today's speech
それで今日のスピーチ
Let's wait for Researcher Lin to explain
リン研究員の説明を待ちましょう
How do we determine that our Tatun volcano is a volcanic volcano
大屯火山が火山であることをどのように判断するのでしょうか
Observations using our SeismicNet
SeismicNetを使った観測
To prove the existence of the magma reservoir under the Tatun Volcanic Group
大屯火山群の下にマグマだまりが存在することを証明する
Then we cover how to use technology to work
次に、テクノロジーを活用して仕事をする方法について説明します。
The early warning data provided by these volcanic eruptions
これらの火山噴火によって提供される早期警戒データ
then do some analysis
それから分析を行ってください
and then be able to know that
そして知ることができるようになる
Fire volcano next to our volcano
私たちの火山の隣にある火火山
what is its current condition
現在の状態はどうですか
We want to be able to coexist with volcanoes
火山と共存したい
These are very important things
これらはとても重要なことです
The whole of Taipei is next to the volcano
台北全体が火山の隣にある
so i want to introduce
それで紹介したいと思います
our speakers today
今日のスピーカー
Researcher Lin Zhenghong
林鄭弘研究員
Graduated from Institute of Geophysics, National Central University
国立中央大学地球物理研究所卒業
Institute of Earth and Environment, Institute of Technology
工業大学地球環境研究所
PhD in Environmental Science
環境科学の博士号
Institute of Earth Sciences
地球科学研究所
Researcher and Deputy Director
研究員兼副所長
Also National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学も
Professor of Peace in the Department of Geological Sciences
地質科学部平和教授
He is now in the Ministry of Science and Technology
彼は現在科学技術省に所属しています
Director of the Tatun Volcanic Observatory
大屯火山観測所の所長
and the Executive Yuan Central Disaster
そして行政院中央災害
member of fire prevention committee
防火委員会の委員
Researcher Lin's research focus
リン研究員の研究の焦点
The focus of the past five years
過去5年間の焦点
including the use of Taiwan's very intensive
台湾の非常に集中的な使用を含む
Earthquake Observation Network
地震観測網
Let's talk about volcanoes
火山について話しましょう
Two important sciences and landslides
2 つの重要な科学と地滑り
Issues related to disaster prevention
防災に関する課題
For seismic data
地震データ用
innovative applications
革新的なアプリケーション
So it will develop landslide monitoring
そこで地滑り監視を開発する
principles and methods
原則と方法
Others have a big contribution
他にも大きな貢献がある
It is the building of the Tatun Volcano
大屯火山の建物です
His research has been awarded twice by the Ministry of Science and Technology
彼の研究は科学技術省から二度賞を受賞しています。
or former National Science Council Distinguished Research Award
または元国家学術会議特別研究賞
It is also the year of the Geophysical Society of the Republic of China
今年は中華民国地球物理学会の年でもあります
Geophysical Contribution Award
地球物理学貢献賞
and many other earth science studies
および他の多くの地球科学研究
Related Young Food Paper Awards
関連する Young Grain Paper Awards
So he brings a very interesting topic today
それで彼は今日とても興味深い話題を持ってきました
We also have quite a few guests here today
今日もたくさんのゲストが来てくれています
Come on, everyone is very interested in this issue
さあ、みんなこの問題にとても興味があります
I'm wasting too much time
時間を無駄にしすぎている
Let us welcome Researcher Lin Zhenghou with warm applause
林正侯研究員を温かい拍手でお迎えしましょう
Vice President Ye
葉副院長
Thank you for your participation
ご参加ありがとうございます
hot summer weather
暑い夏の天気
Everyone also made a special trip here, very touched
皆さんも特別な旅をしてくれました、とても感動しました
that mainly i think
主に私が考えていること
Of course, you may be interested in this topic
もちろん、あなたはこのトピックに興味があるかもしれません
is we put
置いていますか
Laser Jam
レーザーJ
anyway good
とにかく良い
that's mainly this
それは主にこれです
How can we in Taipei follow
台北の私たちはどうやってフォローできるでしょうか
Pompeii linked together
つながったポンペイ
That's actually this
それは実際にこれです
especially in recent years
特に近年
We do a lot of work on the mainland site
私たちは本土の現場で多くの仕事をしています
of course
もちろん
This world happens to have
この世界にはたまたま
Pompeii film in 2014 also
2014年のポンペイ映画も
played
遊んだ
So the whole world is especially Taiwanese
つまり全世界が特に台湾人なのです
special
特別的
Notice
注意
In fact, for such a topic,
実は、このような話題に関しては、
many of my colleagues
私の同僚の多くは
or some friends say
または友達が言います
My topic is too sensational
私の話題はセンセーショナルすぎる
so
それで
You give this title
このタイトルを付けたのはあなたです
just want it
ただ欲しいだけ
to trick everyone
みんなを騙すために
Actually this topic is not
実はこの話題はそうではない
I shouldn't have given it to you
あなたにあげるべきではなかった
conversely
逆に
Because I did work for the mainland website
私は本土のウェブサイトで働いていたため、
So I went to many places regardless of assisting in speeches
ということで、演説の手伝いに関わらず色々なところへ行きました
or popular science speech
または大衆科学のスピーチ
In fact, after each speech
実際、それぞれのスピーチの後、
Mostly people will come to me and ask
たいていの人は私のところに来て尋ねます
Will Taipei become Pompeii?
台北はポンペイになるのか？
So this is what a lot of people care about
ということは、多くの人が気にしているということですね
then i hope today this
それなら今日はこれを願っています
This is more than an hour of these materials
この情報は 1 時間以上あります
After sharing with you
あなたと共有した後
I think everyone will have the answer
誰もが答えを持っていると思います
This very clear answer must be presented
この非常に明確な答えを提示する必要があります
especially in recent months
特にここ数ヶ月
Last one or two years
ここ1、2年
we'll start with this
これから始めます
At the end of last year, the Lihua Institute
昨年末、麗華研究所は
Turn the volcanic disaster into Taiwan's
火山災害を台湾に変える
like earthquake typhoon
地震台風みたいに
This natural disaster like flooding
この洪水のような自然災害は
add volcanic disaster
火山災害を追加する
But everyone knows this is a new thing
しかし、これが新しいことであることは誰もが知っています
the past was never
過去は決してなかった
That's because the Lihua Institute passed this amendment
それは麗華研究所がこの修正案を可決したからです
Therefore, the Executive Yuan and local governments have many
したがって、行政院と地方政府は多くの
related action
関連するアクション
especially taipei
特に台北
Taipei at the end of March this year
今年3月末の台北
Volcanic disasters that are also drills
訓練も兼ねた火山災害
especially for
特にのために
These Beitou under the Yangming Mountain
陽明山の麓にある北投
The inhabitants of Tianmu
天母の住民
let them know in case of volcanic activity
火山活動の場合は知らせてください
It should be dealt with by the Shenbai District
神白区が対処すべきだ
because in human history
なぜなら人類の歴史の中で
Taiwan does not have volcanic disasters
台湾には火山災害がない
Around us, the Philippines, Japan, Indonesia
私たちの周り、フィリピン、日本、インドネシア
In fact, there are volcanic disasters at both ends of the three days
実は3日間の両端で火山災害が発生しています。
Their people and the government have more ideas
彼らの人々と政府はもっと多くのアイデアを持っています
how to face him
彼とどう向き合うか
But Taiwan is really strange
でも台湾って本当に変だよ
So hopefully we're not ashamed of the volcanic disaster
だから私たちが火山災害を恥じていないことを願っています
have more understanding
もっと理解を持ってください
especially in recent months
特にここ数ヶ月
This midnight volcano in Hawaii
ハワイの真夜中の火山
This Longyinliu is on the road
この龍銀柳は道路上にあります
Everyone knows Longyinliu
誰もが知っている龍銀柳
It's very hot and very scary
とても暑くてとても怖いです
Anything that touches it is completely destroyed.
それに触れるものはすべて完全に破壊されます。
If you go to Google and read a lot of reports like this
Google にアクセスしてこのようなレポートをたくさん読むと、
Whether it's a direct lava flow or some breathing
直接の溶岩流であろうと、呼吸であろうと
Or poisonous gas, there are actually a lot of them.
あるいは有毒ガス、実はたくさんあるんです。
In fact, here I would like to point out the following
実は、ここで次のことを指摘しておきたいと思います。
This time, the eruption of this volcano
今回のこの火山の噴火は、
Caused a 6.9 earthquake
マグニチュード6.9の地震を引き起こした
Well, this is actually something that the scientific community or many people are curious about.
実は、これは科学界や多くの人々が興味を持っていることなのです。
Do volcanoes cause earthquakes?
火山は地震を引き起こすのでしょうか？
Then Hawaii not only had a volcanic eruption in 1975
では、ハワイは 1975 年に火山噴火を起こしただけではありません。
Also triggered a larger 7.1 earthquake
さらに大きなマグニチュード7.1の地震も引き起こした
So what's the point of this?
それで、これには何の意味があるのでしょうか？
In fact, if you are interested in earth science or Taiwan
実際、地球科学や台湾に興味があるなら
If there are some concepts of these geology in northern Taiwan
台湾北部にこのような地質の概念があるとしたら
In fact, it will be associated with saying that there is something next to the volcano on the mainland
実は、本土の火山の隣に何かがあるということを連想してしまいます。
We're actually pretty much the triangular fault that seismologists worry about
実際のところ、私たちは地震学者が心配している三角形の断層に相当します。
Then some people talked about whether the volcanic activity would cause
それから、火山活動が原因で起こるのではないかという話もしました。
Triangular Fault Activity
三角断層活動
Evaluation of Triangular Faults by Experts and Scholars
専門家や学者による三角断層の評価
If his entire triangular fault shifts
彼の三角形の欠点全体が変わったら
The earthquake that is likely to be triggered is probably around 6.5 or 6.6
引き起こされる可能性のある地震はおそらくマグニチュード6.5か6.6程度です。
Although not very big compared with this
これに比べるとそれほど大きくないですが、
But he is on the edge of Taipei city
でも彼は台北市の外れにいる
Well, according to some assessments made by the National Earthquake Engineering Center
さて、国立地震工学センターが行ったいくつかの評価によると、
If the triangle fault is active
三角断層が活動している場合
Thousands of houses in Taipei may collapse
台北の数千の家屋が倒壊の可能性
Of course thousands of lives were lost
もちろん何千人もの命が失われた
it's a potential threat
それは潜在的な脅威です
so of course this is extra
もちろんこれは追加です
It's the relationship between volcanoes and earthquakes.
それは火山と地震の関係です。
volcanoes cause earthquakes
火山は地震を引き起こす
Earthquakes trigger volcanoes
地震は火山を引き起こす
but not necessarily
しかし必ずしもではありません
it's a matter of chance
それは偶然の問題だ
in some cases there will be
場合によってはあるでしょう
Fire and rain in May
5月の火と雨
volcanic activity
火山活動
June 2
6月2日
Gualimara, Central and South America
グアリマラ、中南米
This is also the scene of the volcano
ここも火山の光景です
There can be these lava flows, debris flows
このような溶岩流や土石流が発生する可能性があります
you
あなた
Look at Xia Haorui's volcanic eruption
夏ハオルイの火山噴火を見てみよう
from the past few decades
過去数十年から
hardly a single life was lost
命が失われることはほとんどなかった
But relatively Central and South America
でも比較的中南米
Look at this a volcanic eruption
見てください、これは火山の噴火です
dozens of people died
数十人が死亡した
hundreds of people missing
数百人が行方不明
Most of that believed to be missing
そのほとんどが失われていると考えられている
Roughly equal to the number of deaths
死者数とほぼ同じ
then you can see
そうすればわかります
This Central and South American and Xia Haorui
この中南米とシア・ハオルイ
why is there such a big difference
なぜこれほど大きな違いがあるのでしょうか
In addition to the difference in volcanic characteristics
火山の性質の違いに加えて
actually very important very important what is
実はとても重要です とても重要です
this
これ
Xia Haorui has done a lot of work
シア・ハオルイはたくさんの仕事をしてくれました
Japan has done a lot
日本は多くのことをしてきた
Volcanoes like Japan are often erupting
日本のような火山は頻繁に噴火します
But the threat to human life
しかし人命への脅威
really very few
本当にとても少ないです
that's like this
それはこんな感じです
June is the middle of last June
6月は去年の6月中旬
Yindao volcano is erupting
銀島火山が噴火中
that dragon smoke
あのドラゴンの煙
Because Yindao is across the sea
銀島は海の向こうだから
so to this
それでこれに
In fact, this city has no direct
実はこの街には直通の都市はありません。
Dragon Smoke, The Threat of the Cracked Hole
ドラゴンスモーク、ひび割れ穴の脅威
But volcanic ash is actually causing a lot of trouble, too.
しかし、火山灰は実際に多くの問題も引き起こしています。
Then this Bali, Indonesian Bali
それからこのバリ島、インドネシアのバリ島。
This is also the last volcanic activity at the end of June
これは6月末の最後の火山活動でもあります
Then some single things that cause the crowds of tourists
次に、観光客の混雑を引き起こすいくつかの要因
Well, I'm actually going to tell a little story about this.
さて、実際にこれについて少しお話します。
It's the end of June this year
今年も6月末ですね
In fact, Agong Volcano was in October last year
実はアゴン火山は昨年10月に
If everyone has the impression
皆さんにも感想があれば
He also sprayed once
彼も一度スプレーしました
Then this was two months before the eruption of Agong Volcano
それからこれはアゴン火山の噴火の2か月前でした
One day I arrived at the office at eight o'clock in the morning
ある日、私は朝8時にオフィスに到着しました
I got a call from this certain reporter.
とある記者から電話がありました。
radio reporter
ラジオレポーター
he called
彼は電話した
Hello, Mr. Lin, I'm Momo reporter
こんにちは、リンさん、モモ記者です。
so and so
まだまだ
Actually I can't remember
実は思い出せないんです
Well, it's really because of too many reporters.
まあ、それは本当に記者が多すぎるからです。
Then I said yes I remembered
それから私は「はい、思い出しました」と言いました
He said let me ask you a question
彼は、質問させてくださいと言った
I said I thought there was another news
私は別のニュースがあると思うと言いました
he said no
彼はノーと言った
it's a personal accident
それは人身事故です
The reason is that he is going to Paris Island
理由はパリス島に行くから
he wants to celebrate his birthday
他要慶生
25 or something
25かそこら
Just invited a few friends to go to Paris Island to play
友達数人をパリ島に遊びに誘ったところです
As a result, when he was going
その結果、彼が行ったとき、
Paris Island announced that
パリス島が発表した。
The volcano begins to stir
火山が騒ぎ始める
Then he called me and asked me if I wanted to go
それから彼は私に電話して、行きたいかどうか尋ねました
then i will talk to him
それから私は彼と話します
This Indonesian survey
今回のインドネシア調査
Because I don't have the data
データがないので
I don't understand very clearly
あまりはっきりとはわかりません
but i told him
でも私は彼に言いました
if you are not in such a hurry
そんなに急いでいないのであれば
you may wait a little while
少しお待ちください
After Indonesia or the official announcement
インドネシアまたは公式発表後
then you have to judge
それならあなたが判断しなければなりません
Then he probably listened to me
そうしたら彼はおそらく私の話を聞いてくれたでしょう
After two months
2か月後
another morning
別の朝
he just called
彼はちょうど電話したところです
I am a reporter from Mongolia
私はモンゴル出身の記者です
He said sorry I am now
彼は「今はごめんなさい」と言った
Chung Cheng Airport
中城空港
then the night before
それから前の晩に
that waited for two months
2ヶ月も待ったのに
The volcano has finally erupted to the surface
ついに火山が表面に噴火した
He said, should I go?
彼は、「行った方がいいですか？」と言いました。
really two months
本当に2ヶ月
I said you are amazing
あなたはすごいって言いました
you can really count the votes
本当に投票を数えることができます
It was just when the volcano erupted.
ちょうど火山が噴火したときだった。
Then I told him that you might go
それから私は彼に、あなたが行ってもよいと言いました
Maybe there will be a delay at the airport like this
もしかしたらこのまま空港で遅延が起きるかもしれない
But because the eruption of the Grand Agong volcano is the same as
しかし、グランドアゴン火山の噴火は同じなので、
This Paris Island tourist place is about 60 kilometers away
このパリ島の観光地は約 60 キロ離れています
Maybe the volcano will have some impact on the airport
おそらく火山は空港に何らかの影響を与えるでしょう
But at least your life is safe
でも少なくともあなたの命は安全です
should have no scruples
何の躊躇いもないはずだ
so he went
それで彼は行きました
so what does this represent
それで、これはどういう意味ですか
In fact, the volcano does not come instantly
実際、火山はすぐに起こるわけではありません
unlike an earthquake
地震と違って
We can't predict earthquakes yet.
地震はまだ予知できません。
when will you come
いつ来ますか
no one can tell
誰も言えない
But volcanoes basically
でも火山って基本的には
Just like the Japanese and American
日本人とアメリカ人みたいに
or these Indonesian islands of Paris
あるいはインドネシアのパリの島々
they make some audience
彼らはある程度の聴衆を作ります
In fact, I can warn you
実際、私はあなたに警告することができます
He started to move purely
他開始純准移動
you may have to prepare
準備が必要かもしれません
or do something
または何かをする
So overall
全体的に見て
In fact, the simplest way is to say
実際、最も簡単な方法はこう言うことです
You may well imagine that
よく想像できるかもしれませんが、
this is our taipei
ここが私たちの台北です
this is 101
これは101です
This is a photo I took when I climbed to the top of the Jiuwu Peak
これは九烏峰の頂上に登ったときに撮った写真です
Then I put the ancient city of Pompeii and cover it with seven seven seven three
それから古代都市ポンペイをかぶせるように置きました 7 7 7 3
will that be the case
そうなるでしょうか
It's something that many people imagine
それは多くの人が想像することです
then we want to talk today
それでは今日は話したいと思います
Pompeii and Taipei, or this, this, Dalun and Vesvi volcanoes
ポンペイと台北、あるいはこれ、これ、ダルン火山とヴェスヴィ火山
do some comparisons what is the same and what is the difference
何が同じで何が違うのか比較してみます
Then we'll know what happens to him
そうすれば彼に何が起こるか分かるだろう
So according to this very simple introduction, I will divide it into six parts to tell you about it.
それでは、この非常に簡単な紹介文に従って、6つのパートに分けて説明していきます。
The first one is of course nothing more than introducing the relationship between Pompeii and Vesvi to everyone.
一つ目はもちろん、ポンペイとヴェスヴィの関係を皆さんに紹介することです。
We all know each other well
私たちは皆お互いのことをよく知っています
Maybe some people are a little blurry
少しぼやけてる人もいるかもしれない
Let us now briefly introduce the space-time background
ここで時空の背景を簡単に紹介しましょう
let everyone know a little bit
みんなに少し知らせて
And the main part is when the volcano erupts
そしてメインパートは火山が噴火するときです
Why did the entire city of Pompeii be submerged?
なぜポンペイの街全体が水没したのでしょうか？
What kind of disaster, let's introduce it by the way
どんな災害なのか、ついでに紹介しましょう
Then the second is
それから 2 つ目は、
Taipei and Datong volcanoes
台北と大同の火山
Just now the vice president also said
今副社長も言ってた
He is a volcano
彼は火山です
In fact, this is what we have done in the past 10 years
実際、これが私たちが過去 10 年間に行ってきたことです
Some like-minded friends in the academic circles
学界の志を同じくする友人たち
Results from different observations
さまざまな観察から得られた結果
Looks like he's a volcano
火山みたいだ
that especially myself for this
特に私自身がこれに関しては
The work of the magma chamber is actually
実はマグマだまりの働きは、
took me a lot of time
とても時間がかかりました
Sometimes I'm embarrassed to speak in private
プライベートで話すのが恥ずかしいこともあります
In ancient times, I heard people say
昔、人々がこう言うのを聞いたことがあります。
It's a ten-year grind
10年間の苦労だ
I have that deep feeling
そういう深い思いがあるんだよ
I spent more than ten years
10年以上を費やしました
Finally, do some questions that you want to answer
最後に、答えたい質問をいくつか行います
find some answers
いくつかの答えを見つける
The fourth part is
4番目の部分は
TVO stands for Datong Volcano and Mountain
TVOは大同火山と山の略です
Although volcanic
火山だけど
and threatening
そして脅迫する
But it's not such a scary thing
でもそんな怖いものじゃないよ
as long as we are ready
私たちの準備ができている限り
That preparation is actually based on scientific monitoring
その準備は実際には科学的なモニタリングに基づいています
Scientific knowledge can actually provide us with many coping methods
科学的知識は実際に多くの対処法を提供してくれる
that fifth part is fun
その5部は楽しいです
This is not for fun
これは楽しむためのものではありません
for me personally
私個人にとって
I studied ninth subject ninth science
9教科9理科を勉強しました
And it specializes in the study of earthquakes.
そして、それは地震の研究を専門としています。
When I saw the place name of this volcano and the heartbeat of the volcano
この火山の地名と火山の鼓動を見たとき
I'm really a detective
本当に探偵なんです
That heartbeat like a volcano
火山のような鼓動
I believe no one in the world has seen
世界中で誰も見たことがないと思います
when i first saw
初めて見たとき
I don't think there is such a thing
そんな事ないと思うよ
I will report to you later
後ほどご報告させていただきます
Finally, a summary and discussion
最後にまとめと考察
So I took advantage of this explanation with everyone's doctrine
そこで私はこの説明をみんなの教義に利用しました
Let's talk about Pompeii and Mount Vesve first
まずはポンペイとヴェヴェ山について話しましょう
this is the italian peninsula
ここはイタリア半島です
Rome, and south of it is the ancient city of Pompeii
ローマとその南には古代都市ポンペイがあります
Next to the ancient city is the volcano of Weiswei
古代都市の隣にはヴェスヴィ火山があります
that feeling is
その気持ちは
When the Roman Empire was very powerful
ローマ帝国が非常に強大だった頃
good in every way
あらゆる意味で良い
In fact, there are many achievements or VIPs.
実際、実績やVIPもたくさんいます。
very simple VIP
とてもシンプルなVIP
It will be next to the ancient city here
ここの古代都市の隣になります
to buy a villa
別荘を買うために
just come here for vacation
ただ休暇のためにここに来てください
why come here for vacation
なぜ休暇にここに来るのですか
Actually, it's like this all over the world.
実は世界中でこんな感じなんです。
The volcano is the most beautiful
火山が一番美しい
like tokyo in japan
像日本的東京
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
Mount Fuji next to it is also about 60 kilometers away
隣の富士山も約60キロ離れています
That's the spirit of the Japanese
それが日本人の精神です
Or fly to an impossible place
あるいは不可能な場所へ飛んでいく
that's actually like
それは実際に似ています
I will bring it back to Taipei
台北に持って帰ります
Where will the rich people in Taipei be
台北の金持ちはどこにいるのか
You have to be able to afford some mansions
ある程度の豪邸を買う余裕がなければならない
Because there are mountains and water
山と水があるから
just beautiful
ただただ美しい
so like the whole world
全世界と同じように
as long as there are volcanoes
火山がある限り
basically just pretty
基本的にただかわいいだけ
that is
あれは
It's a place that makes you feel comfortable
気持ちが楽になる場所です
but of course it has its threats
しかし、もちろん脅威もあります
2000 years ago
2000年前
The science of course is almost zero
もちろん科学はほぼゼロです
So they didn't think of these things
だから彼らはそんなこと考えなかったんだ
So the ancient city next to it was built here.
そこで隣の古代都市がここに建設されました。
If you have the opportunity to go now
今行く機会があれば
or have the opportunity to
またはその機会がある
This is Vizvi
ヴィズヴィです
This is the current appearance of the ancient city
これが古代都市の現在の姿です
After everyone is excavated
全員発掘したら
The rest becomes a very
残りは非常に大きくなります
A museum that many people visit
多くの人が訪れる美術館
or attractions
またはアトラクション
Then of course the result of this is
そしてもちろん、この結果は次のようになります
When Vizvi volcano erupted
ヴィズビ火山が噴火したとき
Think of this as the plot of the movie
これを映画のあらすじと考えてください
Just cover the entire ancient city next to it.
隣の古代都市全体をカバーするだけです。
Then review these relevant knowledge
次に、これらの関連知識を確認してください
This Vizvi and the ancient city next to it
このヴィズヴィとその隣の古代都市
In fact, the ancient city next to Vizwe is to the south of it.
実際、ヴィズウェの隣の古代都市はその南にあります。
About 10 kilometers away
約10キロ離れたところ
That Huihui's representative said
フイフイの代表者はこう言った
When the volcano erupted, the volcanic ash covered the entire area.
火山が噴火したとき、火山灰が辺り一帯を覆ったのでしょう。
So when it erupted in 2000, it was covered with 6 meters of volcanic ash
そのため、2000 年に噴火したときは 6 メートルの火山灰で覆われました。
In fact, nothing is gone
実際には何もなくなっていない
At that time, the survey said that there were about 20,000 people living in Gai Gai
当時の調査によると、ガイガイには約2万人が住んでいたという。
And with particular emphasis on holiday villas
特に別荘に重点を置いています
Everyone is very leisurely in the process of vacationing there
みんなそこでとてものんびり休暇を過ごしています
It wasn't until the 16th century when the canal was opened that the ancient wall was discovered.
古代の壁が発見されたのは、運河が開通した 16 世紀になってからでした。
But in the 18th century
しかし18世紀には
The king for these ancient artistic incentives
古代の芸術的インセンティブの王様
So he spent a lot of money to put this street in Pompey
それで彼はポンペイウスにこの通りを作るために多額のお金を費やしました
A lot of antiquities, just dig it out
骨董品がたくさんあるので、掘り出してみましょう
That's why people know
だからこそ人々は知っている
This used to be a very large city
ここはかつて非常に大きな都市でした
Although only 20,000
たったの20,000ですが
But you can imagine 20,000 before 2000
しかし、2000 年以前には 20,000 人だったことは想像できます。
that was very lively
とても賑やかでした
a city
街
Then they dug this
それから彼らはこれを掘ります
You see, the streets are very well planned
ご存知の通り、街路は非常によく計画されています
futures-worthy
先物価値のある
and especially this
そして特にこれ
This is above the house of a giant merchant
ここは巨大な商人の家の上です
The money will be written on the ground
お金は地面に書かれます
this welcome money
このウェルカムマネー
Welcome
いらっしゃいませ
It means they are extravagant
それは彼らが贅沢であることを意味します
In fact, if you go to Google to find this document
実際、このドキュメントを見つけるために Google にアクセスすると、
There are many, many criticisms
批判は本当にたくさんあります
It was the Romans at that time
当時はローマ人だった
life of luxury or a lot of negative
贅沢な生活、またはネガティブな生活
delay is in it
遅延はその中にあります
Then of course the last
それからもちろん最後は
They don't know the money is waiting for you
彼らはお金があなたを待っていることを知りません
But the volcano is there too
でも火山もそこにある
In fact, two sides of the same body
実は、同じ体の表裏が
Then why did this happen in the end?
では、結局なぜこうなったのでしょうか？
This is what we want to convey to you
これが私たちがあなたに伝えたいことです
What kind of threat does the volcano pose to me?
火山は私にとってどのような脅威をもたらしますか?
Then this is the original
それでは、これがオリジナルです
These residents were instantly overwhelmed by high temperature
これらの住民はすぐに高熱に襲われました
volcano
火山
When the volcano will also be buried
火山も埋もれるとき
In fact, your bone and flesh tissue is
実際、あなたの骨と肉の組織は
disappeared in an instant
一瞬で消えた
but your body
でもあなたの体は
become hollow
空洞になる
So this is because they poured plaster into it.
これは石膏を流し込んだためです。
look like people at that time
当時の人に似てる
bailed it out
それを救済した
why is that so
どうしてこんなことに
In fact, I want to introduce to you
実は、皆さんにご紹介したいのが、
this pyroclastic flow
この火砕流
this
これ
this is real
これは本物です
Because Pompeii in the 2000s has
なぜなら、2000年代のポンペイは、
I can't prove it
証明できない
But volcanic activity
でも火山活動は
Actually
実際
always have
いつももっている
different places
別の場所
debris flow
土石流
what do you look like in this photo
この写真ではどんなふうに見えますか
super like this
超こんな感じ
Sand Leopard
サンドヒョウ
Anyway, it's just a cloud of ashes.
とにかく、それはただの灰の雲です。
so you can't see
だから君には見えない
shiplike
船的
But this is totally different from the Dust Leopard
しかし、これはダストレオパードとはまったく異なります
Sand Leopard
サンドヒョウ
look
見て
this is very fast
これはとても速いです
100 kilometers per hour 200 kilometers per hour
時速100キロメートル 時速200キロメートル
Then this is very hot
それから、これはとても暑いです
hundreds of degrees of high temperature
数百度の高温
It means you can't escape
つまり逃げられないということだ
if you are touched by it
もしあなたがそれに感動したら
actually probably
実際おそらく
Just like the inhabitants of the valley of Pompeii
まるでポンペイ渓谷の住人のように
almost identical
ほぼ同じ
so you see this
それでこれを見ます
this
これ
There are these villages and houses on the hillside
丘の中腹にはこれらの村や家があります
actually
実際
you can imagine this
これは想像できますね
In fact, there will be nothing left
実際には何も残らないだろう
Pompeii Valley
ポンペイ渓谷
exactly the same result
全く同じ結果
That
それか
you are all real
あなたは皆本物です
this is the philippines
ここはフィリピンです
brand apple
ブランドアップル
when the volcano erupts
火山が噴火するとき
you can see right
あなたは正しく見ることができます
in the lower left corner there is a
左下隅があります
a little truck
小さなトラック
see this stream
このストリームを参照してください
certainly
そうです
run if you can
できるなら走ってください
hop in the car if you can
できれば車に飛び乗ってください
run fast
速く走る
But like I just said
しかし、今言ったように
Can these people escape?
この人たちは逃げられるでしょうか？
basically can't run away
基本的には逃げられない
Because the flow velocity of the broken hole is higher than
破れた穴の流速が速いため、
All road cars are faster
すべての道路車両はより高速です
What's more, this is a path in the field
しかもここは畑の中の小道
that same year
その同じ年に
This silver circle volcano in Japan
日本のこの銀輪火山
You can Google this
これをGoogleで見ることができます
you can see this video
このビデオを見ることができます
He is here, the car is here
彼はここにいます、車はここにあります
Run when you see the tax stream
税金の流れが見えたら実行する
Then the tax stream keeps coming and going.
その後も税金の流れは続いていきます。
Then the screen goes black
その後画面が真っ暗になってしまいます
Then why do you see
ではなぜ見えるのか
Later, they took the camera out of him
その後、彼らは彼からカメラを取り上げました
Since that record is still
その記録が残っているので、
he played it back
彼はそれを再生した
Then restore it to the process at that time
その後、その時点のプロセスに復元します
So the tax and interest flow is actually for the volcanic disaster
つまり、税金と利子の流れは実際には火山災害のためのものである
it's number one
それが一番です
it's inevitable
それは避けられない
And you see it probably can't escape
そして、それはおそらく逃げられないことがわかります
it's very very scary
とてもとても怖いです
Then why is there a tax stream
ではなぜ税金の流れがあるのか
This has a very simple cartoon explanation diagram
非常に簡単な漫画の説明図が付いています
Because when the magma keeps coming up from the crater
マグマが火口から湧き続けるから
That's a thousand-degree high-temperature thing
それは千度の高温のものです
when coming up vertically
垂直に上がってくるとき
after here it starts
ここから始まります
It's going to cool down a bit, but it's still a few hundred degrees left
少しは涼しくなってきましたが、まだ数百度あります
But he starts off kind of turning into something solid
でも、彼は何かしっかりしたものに変わり始めています
It's turning into stone energy
石のエネルギーに変わりつつある
Slowly feel a little cold
だんだんと少し寒さを感じるようになりました
Then but when he keeps piling up
しかし、彼が積み重なったとき
because of gravity
重力のせいで
he will run to him at last
彼はついに彼のところへ走って来るだろう
So when he accumulates a lot
それで、彼がたくさん貯まると、
when running to him for a moment
ちょっと彼に駆け寄ったとき
debris flow
土石流
Underneath are small rocks or these
その下には小さな岩やこれらがあります
large and small stones
大きい石と小さい石
volcanic ash
火山灰
then the whole thing comes down
それからすべてが落ちます
So this is the one that threatens the most
つまり、これが最も脅威となるのです
Then what I just said
それから私が今言ったこと
because it is high temperature
気温が高いので
so you see this just come down
これがちょうど落ちてくるのがわかりますか
At this moment, the whole house burns down
この瞬間、家全体が燃えてしまう
which one is the most
どれが一番多いですか
most modern
最も近代的な
And the best example is
そして、その最良の例は、
Ginsen Volcano in Japan
日本的銀仙火山
This is the eruption of this Yinxian volcano
これがこの銀県火山の噴火です
Then this is the Shimahara room
それではこちらが島原部屋です
at the foot of the mountain
山の麓で
And then this debris flow comes from this hilltop
そしてこの土石流はこの丘の頂上から来ます
Just go down the whole valley
谷全体を下っていくだけです
what happened
それで何が起こったのか
something like this
このようなもの
This is, the debris will come down along this ancient land
これは、この古代の土地に沿って瓦礫が降りてくるだろう
This lower digging is like a river
この下の掘削は川のようです
Mainly these crushed stones
主にこちらの砕石です
will walk along this low ancient land
この低く古代の土地に沿って歩きます
but here it takes a twist
しかし、ここではひねりが必要です
turn these stones
これらの石を回してください
It's heavier, just go this way
重いよ、こっち向いて歩いて
but what does this arrow represent
しかし、この矢印は何を表しているのでしょうか
It's just ash, a lighter substance
それは単なる灰であり、より軽い物質です
moshali it didn't touch the ground
モシャリ、地面に触れなかった
it goes straight from here
ここからはまっすぐ進みます
just rush over
ただ駆け寄ってください
Then rush over here is the village
じゃあ急いでこっちに村だ
There is a primary school in the village
村には小学校があります
we look at this elementary school
私たちはこの小学校を見ます
what happened
どうしたの
This is this crumb coming from here
これはここから来るこのパン粉です
so we are
だから私たちは
Debris is coming from the back of this classroom
この教室の後ろから瓦礫が来ています
Of course you can see the glass
もちろんガラスも見えます
Everything is owned by that crumb
すべてはそのパンくずの所有物です
Those ashes broke it apart
それらの灰がそれをばらばらにした
Whole
全体
But if you look at the other side
でも反対側を見てみると
This is Li Doors and Windows
こちらはLi Doors and Windowsです
You can imagine how high that temperature is
その温度がどれほど高いか想像できるでしょう
That is the temperature of hundreds of degrees of volcanic ash
それは数百度の火山灰の温度です
When it came over in an instant, the entire door and window of Li, which was resistant to a considerable temperature, was deformed.
それが瞬時にやってくると、かなりの温度に耐えていたリーのドアと窓全体が変形した。
So if you imagine that this thing is very hot, the doors and windows are all deformed.
つまり、これが非常に熱いと想像すると、ドアや窓はすべて変形しています。
Then you can imagine people or all these houses
それから人々や家々を想像してみてください
Ordinary traditional wood or houses burn instantly
普通の伝統的な木材や家は瞬時に燃えます
In fact, Yingquan Volcano is in history
実際、英泉火山は歴史の中にあります
In fact, it is a very, very painful lesson for Japan.
実際、これは日本にとって非常に痛ましい教訓だ。
this 1792
これは1792年
Fifteen thousand deaths from this
これにより15,000人が死亡
why hundreds of years ago
なぜ何百年も前に
This is actually one of these natural disasters worthy of our world
これは実際、私たちの世界にとって価値のある自然災害の 1 つです
This model of understanding
この理解モデル
what's going on
どうしたの？
when a volcano erupts
火山が噴火したとき
Just like the eruption of the Xiahaoyi volcano just now triggered a
ちょうど今、Xiahaoyi火山の噴火が引き起こしたように、
about seven earthquakes
7回くらいの地震
then the earthquake
それから地震
Of course, we can imagine the damage caused by the earthquake.
もちろん、地震による被害は想像できます。
even more frightening
さらに恐ろしい
It put this silver inlaid on the other side there was originally a hill
もともと丘があった反対側にこの銀の象嵌を施しました
knocked it all down
すべてを打ち倒しました
It just slides into the sea
そのまま海に滑り落ちてしまう
If it slips into the sea, it will generate a tsunami
海に滑り込むと津波が発生する
So this typical compound disaster
つまり、この典型的な複合災害は
It's a volcanic earthquake and a tsunami
それは火山性地震と津波です
The real 15,000 people may exceed 10,000
本当の15,000人は10,000人を超えるかもしれない
They all died from the impact of this tsunami
この津波の影響で全員が亡くなりました
Then this is the silver inlaid volcano in Kyushu
それからこれは九州の銀象嵌火山です
it's here
ここにあります
So you see after this landslide falls into the sea
この地滑りが海に落ちた後はわかりますか
In fact, the seaside villages around the entire Inland Sea
実際、瀬戸内海全域の海辺の村は、
All residents suffer
住民全員が苦しんでいる
That's why there are so many mountain tiles
だから山タイルがたくさんあるのです
So the Fowles disaster is now more familiar to everyone.
そのため、ファウルズの災害は今では誰にとってもより身近なものとなっています。
Like Japan's Three World Wars and One Earthquake
日本の3度の世界大戦と1度の地震のように
right
右
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
earthquake
地震
tsunami
津波
river disaster
河川災害
The river disaster may actually be
河川災害は実際に起こるかもしれない
In fact, it is more endless than earthquakes and tsunamis.
実際、それは地震や津波よりも無限です。
So this event from the very beginning
ということで、このイベントは最初から
but triggered to the end
しかし最後までトリガーされた
In fact, the most serious is the last
実際、最も深刻なのは最後です
So this loaded disaster
それで、この大きな災害は
In fact, for what we are talking about now
実際、私たちが今話していることについては、
This disaster prevention is very important
この防災はとても大切です
if i know soon
すぐにわかったら
what happened to this
これは何が起こったのか
I have time to avoid subsequent actions
その後の行動を避ける時間がある
or some disaster
あるいは何らかの災害
So the loading hazard is
したがって、積載の危険性は
you are now the whole world for
あなたは今、世界のすべてです
A very important concept of disaster prevention
防災のとても大切な考え方
OK, then say the same
OK、それなら同じことを言ってください
this of course hasn't happened yet
もちろんこれはまだ起こっていません
This is what many American advanced European scientists worry about
これは多くのアメリカの先進的なヨーロッパの科学者が懸念していることです
This is Africa This is North America South America
ここはアフリカです ここは北アメリカ 南アメリカです
That's here on the west coast of Africa
ここはアフリカの西海岸です
there is a volcanic island
火山島があります
The volcanic island is the same
火山島も同じ
When they worry about a volcanic eruption
火山の噴火が心配なとき
volcanic island will collapse
火山島會垮
or these terrific terrains
あるいはこの素晴らしい地形
As long as it collapses, there will be a tsunami
崩れる限り津波が来る
that scientist
あの科学者
It's okay to do some simulations
シミュレーションしてみるのもいいですね
but
しかし
It's scary look at these numbers
この数字を見ると恐ろしいよ
it's 132 meters
132メートルです
which city or 132 if we
どこの都市か、132 か
132 meters, we may all soak in the sea here
標高132メートル、ここでみんなで海に浸かろう
inside sea water
海水の中
That
それか
Although in the west of Africa
アフリカの西にありますが、
But New York, Boston or many cities on the East Coast of the United States
ただし、ニューヨーク、ボストン、または米国東海岸の多くの都市
As long as this tsunami comes
この津波が来る限り
This is really out of hand
これは本当に手に負えない
It is a great threat to human beings and the United States
それは人類と米国にとって大きな脅威です
Will this be an auspicious question?
これは縁起の良い質問でしょうか？
None of us can tell now
今は誰にも言えません
But what day does a real volcanic activity turn into a disaster caused by a tsunami
しかし、実際の火山活動が津波による災害に変わる日はいつですか
auspicious
縁起の良い
is a question worth thinking about
考える価値のある質問です
That
それか
Although in Africa, every week seems to have nothing to do with us
アフリカにいるのに、毎週が私たちには関係のないように思えます
Then I take this opportunity to point out that
そこでこの機会に指摘しておきますが、
Everyone knows that Guishan Island
亀山島は誰もが知っています
We didn't talk about Guishan Island today
今日は亀山島について話さなかった
But Guishan Island is
でも亀山島は
Taiwan's outside of Big Butt Volcano
ビッグバット火山の外側の台湾
volcanic activity volcanic island
火山活動 火山島
Guishan Island
亀山島
if
もしも
If you haven't been there, you can see that these terrains are very steep
行ったことがない方は、この地形が非常に険しいことがわかるでしょう。
If a volcanic event took this piece it arrayed it
火山活動がこの部分を奪った場合、それが配置されました
This is of course a simulation like this
もちろんこれはこんなシミュレーションです
It also creates waves or tsunamis
波や津波も発生します
In particular, our Yilan Plain is actually very flat, right?
特に宜蘭平原は実はとても平らなんですよね？
A wave of 5 meters in the Yilan Plain may be a tsunami
宜蘭平原で5メートルの波は津波の可能性
Maybe the beach is the same
たぶんビーチも同じだろう
If it is 10 meters, there is no need for 1.3 Yilan to be soaked in water
10メートルなら1.3宜蘭を水に浸す必要はない
Of course we don't want this to happen
もちろん、私たちはこのようなことが起こってほしくありません
But things in nature are not about whether we like it or not
しかし、自然界のものは私たちが好むか好まないかではありません。
that we have to be prepared
私たちは準備をしなければならないということ
Can't wait until we wish it didn't happen
そうならないことを願うまで待ちきれません
ok , so let ' s go back to this volcanic disaster
さて、それではこの火山災害の話に戻りましょう
The downdrafts I just told you about are the scariest.
先ほど話した下降気流が一番怖いです。
That longan stream is like this shrimp fish
あのリュウガン川はこのエビの魚のようなものです
The longan stream seems to be very hot, but it's not terrible
龍眼渓はとても熱いようですが、ひどくはありません
There is one that is actually very slow
実際には非常に遅いものがあります
you see it , you run probably past it
あなたはそれを見て、あなたはおそらくそれを通り過ぎて走ります
so longan flow
とても龍眼の流れ
The damage is relatively limited.
被害は比較的限定的です。
In addition, the earthquake we just talked about has also been mentioned.
また、先ほどの地震のことも触れられております。
We're talking about volcanic ash and mudflows
私たちは火山灰と土石流について話しています。
special volcanic ash
特別火山灰
The flowing dragons we just talked about are all at close range
さっき話した流竜が全部至近距離にいる
it's only dangerous if you touch it
触っただけで危険です
But volcanic ash is not
しかし火山灰はそうではありません
it can go far
それは遠くまで行ける
cause you a lot of trouble
あなたに多大なご迷惑をおかけします
This was also last month
これも先月のことです
Yindao volcano erupts again
銀島火山が再び噴火
Luer Island
ルアー島
This is Yindao
ここは銀島です
This is Luer Island City
ここはルアーアイランドシティです
About Luer Island
ルアー島について
No more than about 500,000 people
約50万人以下
small city
小さな町
this volcanic ash
この火山灰
Yin Island is hyperactive
イン島は多動です
I go to Yindao
銀島に行きます
No more than 5 to 10 times
5回から10回まで
I don't remember either
私も覚えていない
but about twice
でも2回くらい
one time you will encounter volcanic ash
いつか火山灰に遭遇するだろう
I have a high memory
私は記憶力が高いです
often just go and see
多くの場合、ただ行って見るだけです
That volcanic ash is like a chimney in Asia
あの火山灰はアジアの煙突のようだ
This Kagoshima city is like this
この鹿児島市はこんな感じです
This is either the sea or the volcanic ash
これは海か火山灰か
So Kagoshima city is very used to
なので、鹿児島市はとても慣れています。
This volcanic ash lives with them
この火山灰は彼らとともに生きています
Mount Aso two years ago
2年前の阿蘇山
Just these cars in the whole neighboring city
近隣の都市全体にこれらの車だけ
all covered
すべてカバーされています
Of course it just makes your life very inconvenient
もちろん生活が非常に不便になるだけです
It will not pose a great threat to your life and property
あなたの生命や財産に重大な脅威をもたらすものではありません
That's a small volcanic eruption
小規模な火山の噴火です
But volcanoes have big eruptions and small eruptions
しかし、火山には大きな噴火もあれば小さな噴火もあります。
Like the Pinnatus in the Philippines that erupted here 900 million years ago
9億年前にここで噴火したフィリピンの羽状突起のように
This is where Manila is located
ここがマニラの場所です
Pingna Tutu is in its northwest
ピンナ ツトゥはその北西部にあります
This volcano has actually been in the past ten or twenty years
この火山は実はここ10年か20年の間にできたものです。
Already a relatively large volcano
すでに比較的大きな火山です
what effect it has
どのような効果があるのか
But this volcano is very lucky
しかし、この火山はとても幸運です
why lucky
なぜ幸運なのか
Because the United States has a so-called this in the Philippines
アメリカはフィリピンにいわゆるこれを持っているので
This Air Force GT is the Clark Air Force GT
このエア フォース GT はクラーク エア フォース GT です
They were two weeks before the eruption
噴火の2週間前だった
Because the USGS in the United States helped with the investigation
米国のUSGSが捜査に協力したため
because of the problems with their F-16 fighter jets
F-16戦闘機の問題のため
So they found out they couldn't do it.
それで彼らはそれができないことに気づきました。
This volcano should erupt within 10 days
この火山は10日以内に噴火するはずです
All Clark Air Force GT F-16's are scrapped
クラーク空軍 GT F-16 はすべて廃棄される
only this one left
これだけ残ってた
This is a broken plane
これは壊れた飛行機です
it can't run so keep it
実行できないのでそのままにしておきます
So a lot of volcanoes were built
それでたくさんの火山が作られました
This is a very successful example of a very successful volcano monitoring
これは火山監視が非常に成功した例です。
That is of course the result of the cooperation between the United States and the Philippines
それはもちろんアメリカとフィリピンの協力の賜物です
then look at this
それからこれを見てください
This though with these volcanoes at close range will
しかし、これらの火山が至近距離にあると、
But this volcano will not only
しかし、この火山はそれだけではありません
nearby will affect
近くに影響が出ます
You see this is the one before the eruption
これが噴火前の様子です
tens of kilometers of this
ここから数十キロ
Six layers of these ash
この灰の6層
When it erupts in June, the whole thing turns red
6月に噴火すると全体が赤くなります
The volcanic ash floats to very, very high altitudes
火山灰は非常に高い高度まで漂います
Then you see it's July, August
そうしたら、もう7月、8月ですね
It was only in December that it slowly returned to its original position.
徐々に元の位置に戻ったのは12月になってからでした。
So for about half a year, the entire volcanic ash floated high above the earth.
そのため、約半年の間、火山灰全体が地上高く漂いました。
Although this is a relatively large volcano this year
今年は比較的大きな火山ですが、
But if a large volcanic eruption like geological time
しかし、地質時代のような大規模な火山噴火が発生した場合、
could cover the entire atmosphere of the entire earth
地球全体の大気全体を覆うことができる
the sun does not come in
太陽が入らない
Life on Earth may even become extinct
地球上の生命は絶滅する可能性さえある
This is history
これは歴史です
That's what the historical evidence says
歴史的証拠がそう言っている
The extinction of some organisms may actually be related to volcanoes
一部の生物の絶滅は実際には火山に関連している可能性があります
Large volcanic eruptions are closely related
大規模な火山噴火は密接に関係している
Then in 2010 this Icelandic volcano
そして2010年にこのアイスランドの火山が
Maybe everyone has the impression
もしかしたら誰もがそんな印象を持っているかもしれません
The entire volcano will float to the continent of Europe
火山全体がヨーロッパ大陸に浮かぶだろう
All flights across continental Europe are suspended
ヨーロッパ大陸を横断するすべての便が運休されています
What about the whole passenger or the economy?
乗客全体や経済はどうなるでしょうか?
They assess a whole bunch of losses
彼らは大量の損失を評価します
Then this is a bigger volcano
そうすると、これはもっと大きな火山です
In fact, it's not just the effect of close range.
実は、これは近距離の影響だけではありません。
In fact, all human beings will be affected
実は人類全員が影響を受けることになる
Let's see how much it erupts
どれくらい噴火するか見てみましょう
Probably the biggest volcano is this one
おそらく最大の火山はこれです
This is the United States on the address
こちらは住所上の米国です
they have three different colors
彼らは3つの異なる色を持っています
That's 2.2 million years
それは220万年です
1.3 million years
130万年
640,000 years
64万年
Area covered by three eruptions of different ages
年代の異なる 3 つの噴火が起こった地域
This geologist does career research
この地質学者はキャリア調査を行っています
outlined
概説した
So there's a super nutrition store under Yellowstone Park
イエローストーン公園の下にスーパー栄養店があります
This also has a movie in production
こちらは映画も制作中です
is also very sensational or very scary
非常にセンセーショナルな、または非常に恐ろしいものでもあります
So the United States actually treats this civil servant of the Huang family very, very seriously.
したがって、米国は実際、この黄家の公務員を非常に真剣に扱っています。
Why?
なぜ？
Of course, if you divide 2.2 by 3, it will come once every 700,000 years.
もちろん、2.2を3で割ると70万年に1回ということになります。
So the last time it was 640,000 seems to be coming soon
前回は640,000だったので、もうすぐ来るようです
If round by cycle
サイクルごとにラウンドする場合
If it is true, it means that they seem to be about to erupt in the tenth time in the tenth time
それが本当なら、10回目に噴火しようとしているということになる。
This is the result of a supervolcano
これは超火山の結果です
Volcanic ash certainly has a big impact
もちろん火山灰の影響も大きい
Let's go back to this lahar
この泥流に戻りましょう
This is a volcanic mudflow in Colombia and the Americas
これはコロンビアとアメリカ大陸の火山泥流です
What is a volcanic mudflow?
火山泥流とは何ですか?
Everyone knows that we have landslides in Taiwan
台湾で地滑りが起きていることは誰もが知っています
It's just water, mud or he just flows down
それはただの水か泥か、あるいはただ流れ落ちるだけだ
It's even scarier at the volcano
火山だともっと怖い
volcanic ash is lighter
火山灰は軽い
so it is easier to flow
だから流れやすくなる
And the ash in the volcanic area
そして火山地帯の灰は
So as soon as you touch the sea, the whole mudslide will come
だから海に触れるとすぐに土砂崩れが起こる
Especially in these high mountains in Central America
特に中米の高山では
usually like jade mountain or this
通常は翡翠山かこれが好きです
or higher these mountains
あるいはそれ以上の山々
it is covered with snow
それは雪で覆われています
But once the volcano came up,
しかし、ひとたび火山が隆起すると、
It's just a high temperature and ice and snow
ただ気温が高くて氷と雪が降っているだけです
Touch some of that snow and it will melt
その雪に触れれば溶けるでしょう
produce a lot of water
水をたくさん生産する
Then the water brings down the ash
それから水が灰を降ろします
The whole shock
ショック全体
There are tens of thousands of people at every turn
毎回何万人もの人がいる
gone
消えた
This is because it is far away from us in Central America
中米では遠いからです。
But in fact, the transmission of information
しかし、実際に情報を発信するということは、
if you look carefully
よく見ると
This is five years or ten years
これは5年か10年です
There is such a big disaster that will come out
こんなに大きな災害が起きるなんて
The mud flow is like this the whole
泥の流れは全体的にこんな感じ
this
これ
Landslides in the South before Typhoon August 8
台風8号の前に南部で土砂崩れが発生
In fact, after blocking these rivers,
実際、これらの川を堰き止めた後、
Then the water goes to the village to flood
そして水が村に流れ込み洪水になる
This is the moment of volcanic eruption
これが火山噴火の瞬間です
Just now we thought that ash lahars
たった今、火山灰が来ると思ったのですが、
Volcanic ash lava flow Water system flow
火山灰溶岩流 水系流
This is an instant disaster
これは即時災害です
But this mudslide
しかし、今回の土砂崩れ
this is endless
これは終わりがない
Why
なぜ
just a typhoon
ただの台風
When the water comes, it will bring a mud flow
水が来ると泥流が起こる
especially the philippines
特にフィリピン
Philippines at every turn
あらゆる場面でフィリピン
as long as a typhoon comes
台風が来る限り
Of course Taiwan is also often affected by typhoons
もちろん台湾も台風の影響を受けることが多いです
big threat
大きな脅威
But like the brand car next to me
でも隣にあるブランド車のように
That is the volcanic fan has been carrying
それは火山扇風機が運んできたものです
poison the river
川に毒を盛る
Then the flood called the whole
それから洪水が全体を呼んだ
to many villages
たくさんの村へ
that may be 30 years
それは30年になるかもしれない
I can't take that volcanic fan away
あの扇風機は離せない
that has always been
それはいつもそうだった
repeat these menacing things
こういった脅迫的なことを繰り返す
Well, the Vesvi and Pompeii
さて、ヴェスヴィとポンペイ
Or Volcano brings an introduction
あるいは火山が紹介をもたらす
we'll go right back to
すぐに戻ります
Our Taipei and Chancellor Hill
私たちの台北とチャンセラーヒル
Of course this is imaginary
もちろんこれは想像です
This is our 101 Dalun Volcano in Taipei Basin
これは台北盆地にある第 101 ダルン火山です
If the Great Looming Volcano erupted
もしも迫りくる大火山が噴火したら
If these lava flows, crater flows, or lahars
この溶岩が流れたり、クレーターが流れたり、泥流が起こったりすると
Anyway, after the advanced stage, they may all go to the Taipei Basin
とにかく、上級段階が終わったら、全員が台北盆地に行くかもしれません
Then if these lava flows block the mouth of Guandu
もしこの溶岩流が官渡の口を塞いだら
Danshui and Keelung can't get out
淡水と基隆は出られない
Will there be this legendary Kangxi Taipei Lake?
この伝説の康渓台北湖は存在するのでしょうか？
won't run out
なくなりません
This is a possibility as long as it happens
それが起こる限り、これは可能性です
In fact, I really hope to compare 101 with Qixing Mountain at this distance.
実際、この距離で101と七星山を比べてみたいと思っています。
Seven Star Mountain is the area we think is most likely to be active
七星山は最も活発になる可能性が高いと思われるエリアです
Well, it's actually less than 15 kilometers
まあ、実際には15キロ未満です
is a very very short distance
とてもとても短い距離です
Very short straight line distance
直線距離非常短
You can imagine this volcano will come up
この火山が現れるのは想像できる
The whole of Taipei is probably similar to that one
台北全体もそれに似ているかもしれない
The guided one has almost the same impact on the city next to it
導かれたものは隣の街にもほぼ同様の影響を与える
Then we also do a little bit of simulation
次に、少しシミュレーションも行います
This is assuming that there is a volcanic eruption in Qixing Mountain
七星山の火山噴火があった場合を想定しています。
What will happen to Longweiliu
ロンウェイリウはどうなるのか
This is the simulated location
ここがシミュレーションの場所です
Then you give me a little closer look
それから、もう少し詳しく見てください
The different colors are its thickness
色の違いは厚みです
or its area of ​​influence
またはその影響範囲
Don't look carefully at this
これを注意深く見ないでください
because you will see where my home is
私の家がどこにあるのかわかるから
In fact, I have always
実際、私はいつも
I made it about four or five years ago
4、5年くらい前に作りました
I have never dared to show off
あえて見せびらかしたことがない
Until recently because of volcanic eruptions it has been
最近まで火山噴火のせいで
Legislated
法制化された
when the government has to face
政府が直面しなければならないとき
So this is just for reference
なのでこれはあくまで参考です
that's for
それはのためです
If Huangzuishan
黄瑞山なら
This is the bottom and this is the golden mountain
ここが底で、ここが黄金の山です
just to the north
すぐ北に
We know Jinshan is very capable
私たちはジンシャンが非常に有能であることを知っています
In fact, many people are very concerned
実はとても心配している人も多いのです
Will it affect the very energy field?
それはエネルギー分野そのものに影響を与えるのでしょうか？
I don't comment on this
これについてはコメントしません
just do a little mock work
ちょっとした模擬作業をするだけです
Of course it will affect the range
もちろん射程にも影響しますが
It all depends on the amount it erupts
すべては噴出量次第だ
If the eruption is a little bit smaller, it will certainly affect a small area
噴火がもう少し小さければ、影響は確実に狭い範囲に及ぶだろう
If the eruption volume is large
噴火量が多い場合
It certainly has a large reach
確かにリーチは広いですね
that eruption is small
その噴火は小さいです
now we don't know
今は分かりません
but i'll tell you later
でも後で言います
if it erupts next month
来月噴火したら
I have a very high chance
非常に高い確率で
will tell everyone
みんなに言うだろう
Will the eruption be big or small
噴火は大きいか小さいか
This is based on some scientific estimates
これはいくつかの科学的推定に基づいています
Well, then this volcanic ash is also what everyone often talks about.
さて、それでは皆さんがよく話題にするのがこの火山灰でもあります。
This is some simulations done with the help of Mr. Wang Guowei from CUHK
これは、CUHK の Wang Guowei 氏の協力を得て行われたシミュレーションです。
In fact, he did it 365 days a year
実際、彼はそれを1年365日やっていた
Different directions according to different seasons
季節ごとに異なる方向
when the volcano comes up
火山が起きるとき
how it should float
どのように浮くべきか
Then of course we have 365 days of data and we are running
もちろん、365 日分のデータがあり、実行しています。
I'm here only spring and autumn
私がここにいるのは春と秋だけ
Of course spring, summer, autumn and winter are different
もちろん春、夏、秋、冬は違います
Every day actually has something to do with the direction of the wind
毎日は実は風向きと関係があるのです
This is from our TVO 6 years ago
これは6年前のTVOからのものです
We just want to say that if the volcano erupts that day
私たちが言いたいのは、もしその日に火山が噴火したら
How should a volcano spread?
火山はどのように広がるべきでしょうか？
Just go to Japan, and spread in the direction of Hainan Island.
そのまま日本に行って、海南島方面に広がってください。
This is an impression
これは感想です
Just tell these phenomena
これらの現象をただ伝えてください
Okay, we talked for a long time, actually.
さて、実際には長い間話しました。
This is what I've always wanted to say if if if
これは私がずっと言いたかったことです もしもし
if the volcano erupts if the volcano erupts
火山が噴火したら 火山が噴火したら
But the real question is whether continental volcanoes will ever erupt
しかし本当の問題は大陸の火山が噴火するかどうかだ
So that's back to our serious scientific question
それで、私たちの深刻な科学的質問に戻ります
That is, we have been around for about ten years
つまり、私たちは約10年間存在しています
A group of people trying to find the answer
答えを見つけようとする人々のグループ
before finding the answer
答えを見つける前に
When I was a student or earth science person
学生や地学関係者の頃
If you read it, you can probably know
読めば分かるかも
This is our topographic map of Taipei
これは台北の地形図です
The red area is the fire dust rock
赤い部分が火粉岩です
Fire dust rocks represent the volcanic eruption
火の粉の岩は火山の噴火を表します
lava on the surface
表面の溶岩
igneous rock body
火山岩
So this is probably like this
ということで、おそらくこんな感じです
That's because in Taiwan we don't have
それは台湾にはそれがないからです。
There is no record of volcanic eruptions in history
歴史上、火山噴火の記録はない
So most people want to say
だからほとんどの人が言いたいのは
Volcanic eruption, Taiwan does not do our business
火山噴火、台湾は私たちの仕事をしません
Taipei will never
台北は決してないだろう
But according to geologists, the stones in these red areas
しかし、地質学者によると、これらの赤い領域にある石は、
do some dating
デートをする
The so-called dating is to find out the age of its eruption
いわゆる年代測定とは、噴火の年代を調べることです。
Was it 10,000 years ago, 100,000 years ago, or 1,000,000 years ago?
それは1万年前でしたか、10万年前でしたか、それとも100万年前でしたか？
They can do it based on that parity year
その平価年に基づいてそれを行うことができます
Do the comparison and get the result
比較を実行して結果を取得します
This is an old picture from the 1980s
これは1980年代の古い写真です
That could have had a little eruption about a million years ago
約100万年前に小規模な噴火があった可能性がある
By 800,000 years
80万年までに
Volcanoes began to emerge from the Chancellor Volcano
チャンセラー火山から火山が出現し始めた
then 400,000 years more
それからさらに40万年
Then came this 100,000 years
それから10万年が経ちました
feel like stopped
止まったような気がする
So because the data is provided until 100,000 years
10万年先までのデータが提供されているので
There is no data for 0.1 million years
10万年分のデータがない
So there is no eruption in history
つまり歴史上噴火は存在しない
This geological researcher told us that it seems to be gone in 100,000 years.
この地質研究者は、10万年後には消滅するようだと語った。
So for a long, long time in the past
だから、ずっと昔から、
Minister Volcano
火山大臣
Or Yang Mingzhang National Park is for fun
または陽明章国立公園は楽しむためのものです
he's not threatening to me
彼は私を脅しているわけではありません
But about ten years of work
でも、10年くらいの仕事で
If we go to mainland volcanoes to see
本土の火山を見に行ったら
This is a surface fumarole hot spring, right?
ここは地表噴気温泉ですよね？
This is a typical volcanic area
ここは典型的な火山地帯です
Especially this geochemical analysis
特にこの地球化学分析
This is the work done by the professors raised by the National Taiwan University
これは国立台湾大学で育てられた教授たちの研究です
He is still equal to the pioneer
彼は依然として先駆者に匹敵する
He did some of these chemical analyzes of the fumaroles
彼は噴気孔の化学分析のいくつかを行いました
just tell us
教えてください
That thing is not a feature of the surface
それは表面の特徴ではありません
but what
でも何
If you step deep into the earth, you will come slowly
地球の奥深くに足を踏み入れれば、ゆっくりとやってくるだろう
That's Teacher Yang Canran
それはヤン・カンラン先生です
met me once and said
一度私に会ってこう言いました
Geochemistry
地球化学
Chemically it looks like it's alive
化学的には生きているように見える
But no one does physics
でも誰も物理学やってないよ
so he advised me to do it
それで彼は私にそうするようアドバイスした
At that time, I just returned from a one-year visit to Japan.
当時、私は1年間の日本訪問から帰国したばかりでした。
Saw a lot of volcanoes in Japan
日本でたくさんの火山を見ました
I gladly jumped in and did it
喜んで飛び込んでやりました
Then I jumped in and now I can't come back
それから私は飛び込んだ、そして今は戻って来ることができない
more and more miracles
ますます奇跡が起こる
Then anyway, I will cast the Earthquake King
それならともかく、地震王をキャストします
so i watched a lot
だからたくさん見ました
There are many, many earthquakes in Daren Mountain
ダレン山では本当にたくさんの地震が起きています
Then in these earthquakes
それから、今回の地震では
What particularly attracts me is
私が特に惹かれるのは、
There are quite
かなりあります
This volcanic earthquake can be seen
この火山性地震が見える
The traditional one is an earthquake on a general fault
従来のものは一般的な断層で発生する地震です
Its appearance is similar to that of volcanoes and earthquakes
その姿は火山や地震に似ている
Its physical properties are completely different
物理的性質が全く異なります
He has a person and he introduces several
彼には人がいて、何人か紹介します
Then like this air-built radar
それからこの航空機レーダーのように
see the crater burst
クレーターの破裂を見る
it's all new
それはすべて新しいです
The rep said he wasn't weathered
担当者は「風化していなかった」と語った
didn't get overshadowed by the 10th
10日までに影が薄れなかった
mean he's new
つまり彼は新人です
Then level the vehicle
次に車両を水平にします
it's a japanese one
それは日本のものです
one of my uncles
私の叔父の一人
sit with me
私と一緒に座った
There may be a drop in the platform when it is found
発見時にプラットフォームに落下がある可能性があります
It means he seems to be moving
彼は動いているようだという意味
rather than stable
安定というより
Then this dating
それから今回のデートは
Especially the last one is the most important
特別最後一項最重要
This is what we used to reason about
これが私たちがかつて推論していたものです
Chen Zonghua Deputy Director
陳宗華副所長
he found russia
彼はロシアを見つけた
found a german
ドイツ人を見つけた
I found it because Russia
ロシアだから見つけた
Then there are quite a lot of volcanoes
それから火山がたくさんあります
Then comes the year of the Volcano Society
そして火山協会の年がやって来ます
Because we don't have good experts in this field
この分野の優れた専門家がいないため
So I invite these foreign scholars to help
そこで私はこれらの外国人学者に協力を呼びかけます。
He set out about 5000 to 6000 years
彼は約5000年から6000年を設定しました
Anyway, he made a mistake.
とにかく、彼は間違いを犯した。
But whether it's 5000 or 6000
でも5000だろうが6000だろうが
This means very high. What does it mean?
これは非常に高いという意味ですが、どういう意味ですか?
In the neighboring country in 99 years
99年後の隣国で
We will open one at the Geological Survey
地質調査所で一つ開けます
Conference of experts and scholars
専門家と学者の会議
Then we talked about Taitai Volcano for a long time
それから私たちはタイタイ火山について長い間話しました
Although there are very strong disputes in the middle
途中で非常に激しい論争がありますが、
Some people say Yes and No
イエスともノーとも言う人もいる
But the final conclusion is that
しかし、最終的な結論は、
general volcano
一般的な火山
Extinct volcanoes or volcanic volcanoes after the whole world
死火山または全世界の火山
The result of our last discussion on Taitai Volcano
タイタイ火山に関する前回の議論の結果
It's a dormant volcano
休火山だよ
What is a dormant volcano
休火山とは
it is a volcano
それは火山です
but it's sleeping now
でも今は寝ています
someday you won't wake up
いつかあなたは目覚めないでしょう
What is the name of this volcano that appeared?
現れたこの火山の名前は何ですか？
like Xia Haoyi
像夏浩儀
You can go to see that magma anytime
そのマグマにいつでも会いに行けるよ
Or go to Aso Volcano
あるいは阿蘇火山に行くか
it's smoking
煙っている
boot smoke
ブーツの煙
This is the volcano that appeared
これが現れた火山です
So the big round volcano is alive
つまり、大きな丸い火山は生きているのです
It's just that it doesn't look active right now
ただ今は活動してないようです
Then with this result
するとこの結果で
So this is the definition of volcanology, which means
これが火山学の定義です。つまり、
Active in ten thousand years
1万年も活動する
you have this record
あなたはこの記録を持っています
I classify it as a volcano
私はそれを火山に分類します
just have a bad record
ただ悪い成績を残しているだけ
special management
特別管理
pay attention to it
それに注意してください
This is the experience above
以上が体験談です
But the phenomenon is
しかし、その現象は、
I personally feel the phenomenon
私もその現象を個人的に感じています
maybe it has more scientific significance
おそらく科学的にはより意味がある
That is, if you can confirm that there is a magma chamber
つまりマグマだまりがあることが確認できれば
like yellowstone park
イエローストーンパークのような
the scientist said
科学者は言いました
There is a big magma chamber underneath
その下には大きなマグマだまりがある
of course it's alive
もちろん生きています
If Yellowstone Park just talked about
イエローストーンパークについて話していたら
last eruption
最後の噴火
The main eruption is 640,000 years old
主な噴火は64万年前のもの
This is ten thousand years old
これは1万年前のものです
That should be ten volcanic
それは10火山のはずです
But Yellowstone can't use rules of thumb
しかしイエローストーンは経験則を使えない
law of phenomena
現象の法則
It's the magma chamber that you found
あなたが見つけたマグマだまりです
live without meaning
意味もなく生きる
This is a general definition of something like
これは次のようなものの一般的な定義です
So the process is
したがって、プロセスは次のとおりです
In fact, for the past five or six years
実はここ5、6年、
Every time because I do Daheng Volcano
大恒火山やってるから毎回
Tell the Ministry of Science and Technology that this is a volcano
科学技術省にこれは火山だと伝えてください
Looks like I'm a volcano
まるで火山のようだ
At that time, the natural Sisi of the Ministry of Science and Technology
その時、科学技術省の天然シシィ
Chen Yigao is also the 17th student of National Taiwan University
陳一高さんは国立台湾大学の17人目の学生でもあります
we are still mature
私たちはまだ成熟しています
every time i meet you i say
あなたに会うたびに私は言います
Where did you say the volcanic magma chamber is?
火山のマグマだまりはどこにあると言いましたか?
When you meet me, ask me where the magma chamber is
会ったらマグマだまりがどこにあるのか聞いてください
I was asked by him for five or six years
5、6年前から彼に頼まれていました
I actually want to talk more
本当はもっと話したいのですが
In fact, I probably have a spectrum how to do it
実際、私はおそらくそれを行う方法のスペクトルを持っています
but no evidence
しかし証拠がない
Then I came up with a very simple concept
そこで私はとてもシンプルなコンセプトを思いつきました
Just use the shadow of the magma chamber
マグマだまりの影を利用するだけ
The concept of this shadow is very simple
この影のコンセプトは非常にシンプルです
we see the shadow of this plane
この飛行機の影が見えます
We don't need to look up to know
知るために調べる必要はない
there is a plane in the sky
空に飛行機があります
Because the sun hits the plane
飛行機に太陽が当たるから
Can't penetrate the plane
飛行機を貫通できない
There is a shadow on the surface
表面に影がある
it's clear
それは明らかだ
The X-ray in medicine is the same for everyone
医療におけるX線検査は誰にとっても同じです
This X-ray hits the bones and tissues
このX線は骨や組織に照射されます。
Because the absorption is different
吸収力が違うから
So if the finger breaks off
それで指が折れたら
see the crack
亀裂を見る
So this is because of the X-ray test
レントゲン検査のせいですね
difference between tissue and bone
組織と骨の違い
Then earth science actually started more than 100 years ago
そして地球科学は実際に100年以上前に始まりました
There is such a concept that
そういう概念があるのですが、
when the earthquake happened
地震が起こったとき
Earth science has long known that
地球科学は長い間それを知っていました
This external combination is AutoCore
この外部の組み合わせは AutoCore です
it is a liquid
それは液体です
This is 2900 kilometers from the surface to the outside
ここは地表から外まで2900キロメートル
is a very, very deep distance
とてもとても深い距離です
But why do scientists know it's a liquid
しかし、なぜ科学者はそれが液体であることを知っているのでしょうか
It is based on the shadow of the S wave
S波の影をベースにしています
Seismic waves hit the red part
赤い部分に地震波が当たる
you can see in this section
このセクションで見ることができます
From this S wave signal
このS波信号から
but you're on the brown side of the back
でもあなたは背中の茶色い側にいます
You can't find a straight S wave
まっすぐなS波は見つからない
It was blocked by OtherCode
OtherCode によってブロックされました
It's just a liquid substance, it can't go through it.
それは単なる液体の物質なので、通過することはできません。
S waves can't penetrate
S波は通らない
Then maybe it's easier to tell you
そうすればもっと伝えやすいかも知れません
That is to say, this is the P wave
つまりこれがP波です
Whenever there is an earthquake
地震が起きるたびに
Anyway, elastic waves will produce P and S
とにかく弾性波はPとSを生み出す
This is a heavy or compression wave
これは重波または圧縮波です
it's a bump
それはでこぼこです
Look at this black
この黒さを見てください
it shrinks and then stretches
それは縮んでから伸びます
It's like hitting a pool ball
ビリヤードのボールを打つようなものだ
So the energy is transferred in one
つまり、エネルギーは一度に伝達されます
What is the S wave
S波とは何ですか
S waves are like snakes
S波は蛇のようだ
it just twists and shears
それはただねじったり、剪断したりするだけです
So one is a linear motion
つまり、1 つは直線運動です
a sideways twist
横にひねる
Then this is of course simpler
それなら、これはもちろん簡単です
for simplicity
簡単にするために
That is to say, if the left side is a solid
つまり、左側が固体の場合、
on the right is a liquid
右側は液体です
What is the difference between solid and liquid
固体と液体の違いは何ですか
solid is this
これはしっかりしています
Between each molecule and the powder molecule
各分子と粉末分子の間
caught by chemical pieces caught well
化学物質に引っかかる 破片がよく引っかかる
it can't run around
走り回ることはできない
It means you're on my left and you're on the left
つまり、あなたは私の左側にいて、あなたは左側にいるということです
you can't run to the right
右に走ってはいけない
but what about liquid
しかし液体はどうでしょうか
You can run with liquid
液体を入れても走れます
is liquid or gas
液体か気体か
Meaning it doesn't have these brown sugars
つまり、黒砂糖が入っていないということです
see you grab
見てください、掴んでください
So what do these two different behaviors cause?
これら 2 つの異なる動作は何を引き起こすのでしょうか?
P4 If you turn around from this side by external force
P4 外力により手前から曲がると
it will
そうなる
it will be like this
このようになります
and then this
それからこれ
this shape this
この形はこれ
So P4 will transfer energy
つまり、P4はエネルギーを伝達します
Then you when this one comes running
それから、これが走ってきたとき、あなたは
This S wave because it has sugar yellow
シュガーイエローがあるからこのS波
it will pull over and the sugar yellow will elongate
それは引っ張られ、砂糖の黄色は伸びます
so this will bring
これにより、
then take one by one
それから一つずつ取ってください
So the S wave will pass like this
S波はこうやって通過していきます
So when solid
それで、固まったら
Both P and S pass
PもSも合格
but when liquid
でも液体のときは
P4 can pass
P4は通過できる
S wave because these two don't have any
この二人は何も持っていないのでS波
that relationship
その関係
so
それで
This hole this one won't move
この穴は動かない
Take a very simple ratio
非常に単純な比率を取る
everyone sit here
みんなここに座ってください
if we hold hands
私たちが手をつないだら
is solid
しっかりしている
when one of them leans back
そのうちの1人が後ろにもたれると
The one next to it will also treat it
隣の人も治療してくれる
so it will pull one by one
それで一つずつ引っ張っていきます
So this is the characteristic of S wave
これがS波の特徴です
If we don't hold hands, it will be liquid
手を繋がないと液体になってしまう
one of them lay forward
そのうちの1人は前に横たわっていました
Lie forward, the one next to it won't be dried
前に寝てください、隣の人は乾きません
is a property of solid liquids
固体液体の性質です
Based on this, we can test that
これに基づいて、次のことをテストできます。
Is there any liquid or solid in the earth?
地球には液体や固体はありますか?
this just
これだけ
Okay, so we imagine that
さて、私たちはそれを想像します
Except for Otocore, the earth is external and liquid
オトコアを除いて地球は外部にあり液体です
kernel
カーネル
Not this magma chamber
このマグマだまりではない
It should be that the magma with high temperature is liquid
高温のマグマは液体であるはずです
So I was thinking that S wave will definitely disappear after hitting this point, right?
ということは、ここまで来るとS波は確実に消えるだろうと思っていましたね。
Okay, then I have deployed a lot of seismographs here in Yangmingshan.
さて、私はここ陽明山にたくさんの地震計を配備しました。
Then take advantage of the very deep bottom
次に、非常に深い底を利用します
We have many large and deep earthquakes off the coast of Yilan
宜蘭沖では大規模で深い地震が何度も発生しています。
and then straight up from the bottom
そして下からまっすぐ上に
then hit our area
それから私たちの地域に行きます
Then I'll check
それから確認します
You will see the blue seismic stations all can see the S-Bow
青い地震観測所が見えます。すべて S-Bow が見えます。
The only thing is that the red area cannot see S-Bow
唯一のことは、赤い領域にはS-Bowが表示されないということです
Of course, P-Bow and S-Bow look a bit professional
もちろん、P-Bow と S-Bow は少しプロフェッショナルに見えます
but it's not that hard
でもそれはそれほど難しいことではありません
I put the red and blue records on the next one
赤と青のレコードを次のレコードに置きます
Here's where P-Bow arrives
ここにP-Bowが到着します
Then the S-Bow arrives like it's clear
そして晴れたようにS-Bowが到着
But when the seismic waves hit the magma chamber
しかし、地震波がマグマだまりにぶつかると、
P-Bow is penetrable
P-Bow は貫通可能です
S-Bow can't find it at all
S-Bowは全然見つからない
It just disappears, disappears, and there is a shadow
ただ消えて消えて影がある
So this diagram says
したがって、この図は次のことを示しています
S-Bow disappeared when hitting the magma chamber
S-Bowはマグマだまりに衝突して消滅した
S-Bow runs out when you miss it
S-Bow は逃すとなくなります
According to this is very simple, we will draw a cartoon picture
これは非常に簡単ですので、漫画の絵を描きます
The magma chamber is here. If you hit yellow, this side station
マグマだまりはここです 黄色のところはこちら側の駅です
If you can't see it, you're blocked
見えない場合はブロックされています
If this is true, we also repeat the verification that
これが本当であれば、我々も検証を繰り返します。
If the magma is fixed here, the S wave cannot pass through it, but what about the P wave and the heavy wave,
ここにマグマが固定されていればS波は通過できませんが、P波や重波はどうなるでしょうか。
Heavy waves, solids and liquids are all fine, they can penetrate all of them,
重い波も、固体も液体も大丈夫、すべてを透過できます。
Although it can penetrate, but it will slow down,
貫通はできるけど速度は落ちますが、
Because it is liquid, it will go slower,
液体なのでゆっくり進みますが、
So I will walk here together as the side,
だから私はここを側として一緒に歩いていきます
These two it only goes so far,
この 2 つだけでは限界がありますが、
This is a group of four, but it is very clear that we see the earthquake hit here,
これは 4 人のグループですが、ここで地震が発生したことがはっきりとわかります。
We got a signal on the surface,
地上で信号を受信しました
Then this is a simulation, if you hit the magma, it will slow down here,
それからこれはシミュレーションです、マグマにぶつかるとここで速度が下がります、
Then the S wave disappears, and the right hand side is our observation,
その後、S 波が消え、右側が観測値になります。
That is, the wave that does not hit the magma solid will follow the distance,
つまり、マグマ固体に当たらない波は距離を追うことになり、
Arrive here at the appearance of probably black,
おそらく黒い外観のこちらに到着し、
But once the magma is solidified, it will not be here, it is a little slower,
でもマグマが固まるとここには来なくなる、少し遅くなる、
So when you look at the S wave, you can’t see it, and then the P wave is similar again,
つまり、S 波を見るとそれは見えなくなり、P 波は再び同様になります。
To me, this is the space of no doubt,
私にとって、ここは疑いようのない空間なのですが、
There is a liquid substance under the ground,
地下には液体の物質が存在しており、
It is said that the liquid substance is, um, what is missing is magma, it is water,
液体物質は、ええと、足りないものはマグマです、それは水です、と言われています。
That's impossible,
それ無理、
Why? At 20 km the water will be squeezed out
なぜでしょうか? 20km で水が絞り出されます。
Because the density of magma is closer to that of rock
マグマの密度は岩石の密度に近いため
it can be retained so it can't be water
保持できるので水ではありえない
So of course magma is the best and only explanation
したがって、もちろんマグマが最良かつ唯一の説明です
Then its size is about
それからそのサイズは約です
GOO la 70 square kilometers
GOOラ 70平方キロメートル
How big is 70 square kilometers
70平方キロメートルってどのくらいの大きさですか
It's its area
それはその地域です
About a quarter of the size of the administrative district of Taipei City
台北市の行政区の約4分の1の広さ
let everyone be grateful
みんなに感謝しましょう
A little bigger than Siling District, a little more than Xinyi Songshan in the East District.
四陵区より少し大きく、東区の信義松山より少し大きいくらいです。
slightly smaller
わずかに小さい
what's the point of this
これはどういう意味ですか
As long as one cubic kilometer of magma comes up
1立方キロメートルのマグマが湧き出てくる限り
probably just like
おそらく同じように
It is so big before reaching the platform
ホームに着くまでにこんなに大きいのに
Maybe the deep sea is a little bigger than the deep sea eruption
もしかしたら深海は深海の噴火よりも少し大きいかもしれません
that would be terrible
それはひどいことになるだろう
So it's not like all this magma will burst the surface
つまり、このマグマがすべて地表を破裂するわけではない
Actually it's only 1%
実はそれはたったの1%なんです
A percentage of the earth's surface will actually cause a volcanic eruption
地球の表面の一部が実際に火山噴火を引き起こす可能性があります
So it's very dangerous
だからとても危険なんです
Well, of course this is
まあ、もちろんこれは
Because of the results of these studies
こういった研究結果のおかげで
So the central
それで中央は
except the legislature
立法府を除いて
Then the Executive Yuan has done some
その後、行政院はいくつかのことを行いました
this coping
この対処法
So a business plan for a volcanic disaster
火山災害に対する事業計画
no matter central place now
今は中心部に関係なく
must follow above
上記に従う必要があります
Some mechanisms of this strain
この菌株のいくつかのメカニズム
Alright, let's find out the sales and trading team
わかりました、販売および取引チームを探しましょう
but for me
でも私にとっては
In fact, the challenge is greater
実際には、課題はさらに大きくなります
The reason is that this is
その理由は、これは、
Our so-called colleague Huang Xinhua did it
私たちのいわゆる同僚である黄新華がそれをやった
what to do at this yellowstone park
このイエローストーン公園で何をするか
There is a extension library under it
その下に拡張ライブラリがあります
there is a
ある
that's in taiwan
それは台湾にあります
I think it's 20 kilometers
20キロくらいあると思います
what we see is this one
私たちが見ているのはこれです
actually more worried
実際にはもっと心配です
do you have this money
このお金を持っていますか
That's because our resolution is limited
それは私たちの解像度には限界があるからです
so I dare not speak
だからあえて話さない
Is there any upper land?
上の土地はあるのでしょうか？
So the Ministry of Science and Technology gave me an order saying
そこで科学技術省は私に次のような命令を出しました。
keep looking
見続ける
we'll just mention one
一つだけ触れておきます
pretty big plan
かなり大きな計画
Make them like this for the ninth month
9ヶ月目はこうしてみよう
we are in northern taiwan
私たちは台湾北部にいます
Ministry of Secret Codes for Seismic Stations
地震観測所の秘密暗号省
I hope that Datun Mountain and Guishan
大屯山と亀山を願っています
Find it in the magma chambers of these two volcanoes
これら 2 つの火山のマグマだまりで見つけてください。
In fact, we also found the magma chamber on Guishan Island.
実際、亀山島でもマグマだまりが発見されました。
The article is under review
記事は審査中です
should be out soon
すぐに出るべきです
So there is definitely a magma reservoir under Guishan
つまり亀山の地下にはマグマだまりがあるのは間違いない
So we want to take this size depth
したがって、このサイズの奥行きをとりたいのです
Hope to find it out
それが見つかることを願っています
So I hope to finish this project in four years
だからこのプロジェクトは4年以内に終わらせたいと思っています
That's the black street station of our first year department
それが私たちの1年生部門のブラックストリートステーションです
Then the next year I hope to fill the white
そして来年は白を埋めたいと思っています
Then in the third and fourth years, I can really do some analysis and research
3年目、4年目になると、本格的に分析や研究ができるようになります。
Next is this TVU
次はこちらのTVU
This volcano looks like it's on fire
この火山は燃えているように見えます
eruption cannot be ruled out
噴火の可能性も否定できない
what shall we do
何をしましょうか
This fear is often rooted in ignorance
この恐怖は無知に根ざしていることが多い
This is the Aso volcano just mentioned in Japan
これが先ほど日本で言及した阿蘇火山です
There are railroad houses and a lot of residents inside.
鉄道の家があり、中には多くの住民が住んでいます。
This is a big crater
ここは大きなクレーターです
people live in it
人々はそこに住んでいます
lived for decades
何十年も生きた
20 years, hundreds of years, maybe a thousand years
20年、数百年、もしかしたら千年も
they didn't panic
彼らはパニックにならなかった
live inside the crater
クレーターの中に住んでいる
Where is that reason?
その理由はどこにあるのでしょうか？
This one is more interesting
こっちの方が面白いよ
This is Chapelle May 1 spray 8
こちらはチャペル メイワン スプレー 8
Director Chen of the NCD
あのNCD、あのチェン監督
send me this one and say
これを送って言ってください
wow this is great
うわー、これはすごいですね
You see, this old beauty seems very handsome
ほら、この年老いた美女はとてもハンサムに見えるよ
The volcano is covered in ashes
火山は灰に覆われている
he plays golf there
彼はそこでゴルフもします
The reason is that they are not afraid
理由は怖くないからです
The reason not to be afraid is not because you have courage
怖くないのは勇気があるからではない
because of what ? with this backer
なぜこの支援者と？
This is Chapelle Volcano off this station
ここはこの駅のすぐそばにあるシャペル火山です
Bottom this next to this
これの隣に
Less than 100 meters to the crater
火口まで100メートル未満
When I visited last year, I asked him
去年訪れたときに聞いてみた
How deep is your crater along the river?
川沿いのクレーターの深さはどれくらいですか?
He said 3 kilometers
彼は3キロと言った
I said wow, 3 kilometers away, you still dare to live here
私は言った、すごい、3キロ離れているのに、まだここに住む勇気があるのね
This has a history of 100 years
これには100年の歴史があります
Why?
なぜ？
The volcano will erupt 8 will not be instant
火山は噴火するでしょう 8 すぐには噴火しません
There will be action, there will be warning
行動が起こり、警告が起こる
so they can
それで彼らはできる
so they are in good hands
だから彼らは良い状態にある
Therefore, they use earth sciences to monitor all kinds of air, surface or underground.
したがって、彼らは地球科学を利用してあらゆる種類の物質を監視しています。
as long as there is movement
動きがある限り
Before the volcano erupts, there should be
火山が噴火する前に、
Like the one from Weisway just now, it is the oldest one a few years ago
先ほどのワイズウェイのものと同じく、数年前の最も古いものです
18.4 billion years old
184億歳
This is a very old painting
これはとても古い絵です
that is the status quo
それが現状です
Isn't this Pompeii already covered?
このポンペイについてはすでに取り上げられているのではないでしょうか？
Why is there still a volcano observatory?
なぜ火山観測所がまだあるのですか？
original intention is
本来の意図は
sorry
ごめん
Pompeii south of Visway
ヴィスウェイの南にあるポンペイ
There is also a Napolis to the north of him
彼の北にはナポリスもあります
So this also needs to be Watched
したがって、これも監視する必要があります
to observe
観察すること
That day the volcano will
その日、火山は
unlucky for these people
この人たちにとっては不運だ
so they have to monitor
だから彼らは監視しなければならない
So we are at Datong Volcano
それで私たちは大同火山にいます
We're going to set up an observatory
天文台を設置する予定です
This is the hardware provided by Yangmingnan National Park
これは陽明南国家公園が提供するハードウェアです
it's a nice environment
素敵な環境です
We have borrowed four or five offices here
ここに4つか5つのオフィスを借りています
Then build this observatory
それからこの天文台を建ててください
At the beginning, the Ministry of Science and Technology and the Ministry of the Interior
当初は科学技術省と内務省が
Because the national public health belongs to the Ministry of the Interior
国家公衆衛生は内務省に属しているため
We have a MEMO
MEMOがあります
and then construct this
あとはこれを構築するだけです
So the Ministry of Science and Technology paid the main money
それで科学技術省が主なお金を支払いました
Our Chinese is also the main person
私たちの中国人も主役です
not only me
私だけではありません
Many technicians at our Earth Institute
地球研究所には多くの技術者がいます
researchers participate in
研究者が参加する
Ministry of Science and Technology
科学技術省
Hardware equipment from the Ministry of the Interior
内務省のハードウェア機器
Out of electricity, out of house, out of air-conditioning
停電、家の外、エアコンの停止
Because this is not actually a
これは実際にはそうではないため、
Very simple one unit can perform
非常にシンプルな1台で実行可能
So we integrated a lot of
そこで私たちは多くの機能を統合しました
Then this is our observatory
それではここが私たちの天文台です
The location of the instrument distribution
楽器の配布場所
This is the triangular fault just mentioned
これが先ほどの三角断層です
This is the entire area of ​​Yangmingshan
ここは陽明山一帯です
Conceptually this is a picture
概念的にはこれは絵です
That is, we have spread a lot on the surface
つまり、私たちは表面上にたくさんのことを広めました
different instruments
さまざまな楽器
Including seismographs Crustal deformation Geochemistry
地震計を含む 地殻変動 地球化学
ground temperature sprayed in
地表温度が吹き付けられる
I always hope that as long as the volcano has erupted before
以前に火山が噴火したことがある限り、私はいつもそう願っています
We believe that there should be some anomalies in these
これらには何らかの異常があるはずだと考えています
Then we have to report to the government, the people and everyone.
それから政府、国民、皆さんに報告しなければなりません。
Said the volcano may have started to restless
火山が落ち着きを失い始めたかもしれないと言った
This is our real-time monitoring station
これは当社のリアルタイム監視ステーションです
So we send a lot of real-time news to this screen for discussion
そのため、ディスカッションのために多くのリアルタイム ニュースをこの画面に送信します
Then this picture is the enlarged one just now
では、この写真は今拡大したものです
This four-one picture is if people go up
この4-1の絵は人が上がれば
In fact, the surface of the earth will deform the crust, right?
実際、地球の表面は地殻を変形させますよね？
be raised or arched
盛り上がるかアーチ型になる
We have to rely on GPS to tilt the level
レベルを傾けるには GPS に頼らなければなりません
we can measure the deformation of its crust
地殻の変形を測定できます
And then here's like volcanic gas
そしてここには火山ガスのようなものがあります
Because its concentration composition will also change
濃度組成も変化しますので
It is conceivable that the temperature will also increase
気温も上がると思われます
that special seismic activity
その特別な地震活動
Because my specialty is seismic activity
私の専門は地震活動なので
that seismic activity is
その地震活動は
Of course I know best
もちろん私が一番よく知っています
and I believe the most useful
そして私はそれが最も役に立つと信じています
a concept map
コンセプトマップ
The usual magma has not changed for 10 kilometers, 20 kilometers I don’t know
いつものマグマは10キロも20キロも変わらない、わからない
Because the magma is hot
マグマは熱いから
So there's a little bit of an earthquake on it
それで少し地震が起きました
But if the magma runs from A to B like this
でもマグマがこのようにAからBに流れたら
Lava will come up
溶岩が出てくるよ
what will happen to this incredible thing
この信じられないことはどうなるでしょうか
Due to the change of temperature and pressure above
上記の温度と圧力の変化により、
There will be many, many earthquakes
たくさん地震が起こるだろう
For example, our Yangmingshan is now one month
たとえば、私たちの陽明山は今1か月です
Maybe only three or five earthquakes every day
おそらく毎日 3 回か 5 回の地震しか起こらない
If the magma goes up
マグマが上がれば
i predict or i imagine
予測したり想像したりする
There may be 500 to 1000 earthquakes in one day
1日に500～1000回の地震が起こる可能性がある
That's obviously different
それは明らかに違うよ
Our record map is secretly referring to earthquakes
私たちの記録地図は密かに地震について言及しています
I don't want to see but when I see
見たくないけど見たら
That means there is follow-up action
つまり、後続措置があるということです
when the moon goes up
月が昇るとき
This is called a volcanic eruption.
これを火山噴火といいます。
But you can say from B to C
しかし、BからCまで言うことはできます
When this earthquake B, the earthquake may be 3 kilometers
この地震Bの場合、地震は3キロメートルになる可能性があります
There is one kilometer left at C
C地点は残り1キロです
here maybe
ここで多分
5km or 10km
5kmとか10kmとか
what does this mean
これは何を意味するのでしょうか
We only need the depth of the earthquake to determine it
地震の深さを判断するだけで十分です
Must slowly change from deep to front
深いところから手前にゆっくりと変化しなければなりません
It's maybe 20 days from here to here
ここからここまで20日くらいかな
I know it runs 0.5 kilometers a day
1日0.5キロ走るのは知っています
If it is 3 days from here to here
ここからここまで3日なら
I just saw it run 0.2km a day or something
1日0.2kmとか走っているのを見ました。
can i estimate
推定してもいいですか
I guess it's okay
大丈夫だと思います
That could be 10 days or a week to the surface
地上に現れるまで10日か1週間かかるかもしれない
so i can't tell you guys
だから皆さんには言えません
Will the volcano erupt next year?
来年火山が噴火するでしょうか？
This time is too far away, I can't follow
今回は遠すぎてついていけない
But if say a month the volcano will
しかし、たとえば 1 か月あれば、火山はそうなるだろう。
The volcano will erupt in a month
火山は一ヶ月以内に噴火するだろう
I am sure I will see the exception
必ず例外が発生すると思います
I'll see a spike in these earthquakes
これらの地震は急増するだろう
Of course it's not just an earthquake
もちろん地震だけではありません
That is, the volcanic gas is immediately deformed, low temperature
つまり、火山ガスはすぐに変形し、低温になります。
There should always be exceptions to this
これには常に例外があるはずです
When integrated, there should be good information to judge
統合すると、判断に適した情報が得られるはずです
That also means that this is the approximate timeline
これは、これがおおよそのタイムラインであることも意味します
I can roughly estimate how long it might take to reach the surface
地表に到達するまでにどれくらい時間がかかるかを大まかに見積もることができます
Similarly, if I see Huangzui Mountain
同様に、黄瑞山を見たら
Earthquakes are coming out of Huangzui Mountain
黄嘴山から地震が起きています
I just want to say that Huangzui Mountain may approach the surface along the river.
ただ言いたいのは、黄瑞山が川に沿って地表に近づく可能性があるということです。
If it is in the big oil pit
大きなオイルピットの場合
I knew that the big oil pit might move around along the river
大きな油田が川に沿って移動する可能性があることはわかっていました
so i know something
だから私は何かを知っています
Then if I see a big oil pit, a small oil pit
大きなオイルピットが見えたら、小さなオイルピットも
Why is Huang Zuishan so troublesome?
なぜ黄瑞山はこんなに厄介なのでしょうか？
The rep said, wow, it's serious all of a sudden.
代表者は「わあ、いきなり大変なことになった」と言いました。
it's comprehensive, right?
それは包括的ですよね？
So the size time
それで、サイズ時間
Probably scientifically, I can make an estimate
おそらく科学的に推定できるでしょう
So we did a lot of observations
そこで私たちはたくさんの観察をしました
But of course there have been no volcanic eruptions since
しかし、もちろんそれ以来火山の噴火は起こっていません。
it's very lucky
それはとても幸運です
But even if we don't have volcanic eruptions
しかし、たとえ火山の噴火がなかったとしても、
we do scientific research
私たちは科学研究を行っています
We still found a lot of interesting things
まだまだ面白いものをたくさん見つけました
what is interesting
何が面白いのか
we are earthquake
私たちは地震です
I will talk about the earthquake part
地震の部分について話します
this is
これは
Each line is a record of twenty hours a day
各行は 1 日 20 時間の記録です
A black is fifteen minutes
黒は15分です
and then the blue one for an hour
それから青いものを1時間
It's two hours, twenty-four hours
2時間だ、24時間だ
Show you four or five hours in the middle of the night
夜中の4、5時間見せてよ
The ground is shaking
地面が揺れています
When I first saw this ten years ago I wanted to say
10年前にこれを初めて見たとき、こう言いたかった
That's the car
それがその車です
What is the wind and tide?
風と潮とは何ですか？
That is, there are many people in Yangmingshan anyway.
それは、陽明山はとにかく人が多いということです。
but i want to say
でも言いたい
The time pair is ten o'clock in the middle of the night to two and three o'clock in the morning
時間は深夜10時から午前2時、午前3時までです。
impossible to have a car
車を持つことは不可能
unless it's something weird
何か変なことじゃない限り
Well, based on science, we certainly believe it is
科学に基づいて、私たちは確かにそれがそうだと信じています
is to believe in science
科学を信じることです
So there should be no human activity
だから人間の活動はあってはならない
That should be this natural phenomenon
それがこの自然現象のはずだ
So it's as simple as
したがって、それは次のように簡単です
You can imagine if this pot is slapping and burning
この鍋がバタバタと燃えている様子を想像してみてください
if heated
加熱した場合
when the pressure builds
圧力が高まったとき
Doesn't the lid of the pot cause steam?
鍋の蓋から蒸気が出ることはありませんか？
will it vibrate all the time
ずっと振動してるのかな
The vibration is likely to cause
振動により起こりやすいのは、
The concept that the entire surface of the earth is shaking
地球の表面全体が揺れているという概念
That's also very interesting
それもとても興味深いですね
This is a certain earthquake
これはとある地震です
is one, two, three, four
は 1、2、3、4 です
More than a dozen earthquake battles all counted a signal at the same time
十数回の地震戦はすべて同時に信号を数えた
Then this signal is called to look like a drop
次に、このシグナルが呼び出され、ドロップのように見えます。
This is an earthquake record in the shape of a water drop in the scientific community
これは科学界の水滴の形をした地震記録です
This is similar to the earthquake in Hualien, Chiayi, for example.
これは、例えば嘉義花蓮市の地震と似ています。
completely different shape
全く違う形
These earthquakes in Hualien, Chiayi look
花蓮、嘉義の地震は次のようになります。
We look at P wave X wave Heptathlon people
P波X波七種競技者を見る
They all do this every day
彼らは皆これを毎日やっています
But this one can't see the P wave at all
しかし、これはP波がまったく見えません
X wave saw a very special
X ウェーブは非常に特別なものでした
Just like a drop of energy
まるでエネルギーの一滴のように
Then if you look closely at its frequency
次に、その周波数をよく見てみると、
that's more interesting
それはもっと面白いです
it is single frequency
それは単一周波数です
it's about three to a few hertz
およそ3ヘルツから数ヘルツです
single frequency signal
単一周波数信号
How can there be a single-frequency signal in nature?
自然界に単一周波数信号はどのようにして存在するのでしょうか?
it's incredible
それは信じられないです
That's easy, of course, let's talk about
もちろんそれは簡単です、話しましょう
Everyone play enough instruments
誰もが十分な楽器を演奏します
If you wave the strings of one of the lamps
ランプの紐を振ると
It's all single frequency, right?
すべて単一周波数ですよね？
That means it looks like someone is rippling a string underground
つまり、誰かが地下で糸を波打っているように見えるということです
Of course it's impossible
もちろんそれは不可能です
The real reason is that
本当の理由は、
Because the magma under the ground
地下にはマグマがあるので、
it actually has these
実際にはこれらがあります
When the gas or liquid in these cracks
この亀裂に気体や液体が入ると、
It only takes a change in pressure
圧力の変化だけが必要です
or move quickly
または素早く移動する
The whole rock wall will shake
岩壁全体が揺れるだろう
The frequency of shaking is determined by its width and length
揺れの周波数はその幅と長さによって決まります
like peeling a spin
スピンを剥がすように
If the thickness and length of its spin are fixed
スピンの太さと長さが一定の場合
its frequency is fixed
その周波数は固定されています
the width of the crack
亀裂の幅
Its geometry is the same as it is a single frequency
その形状は単一周波数であるため同じです
This is really our interpretation
これは本当に私たちの解釈です
Rothstein
ロススタイン
super like rostin
ロスティンに超似てる
called English they called Tornitos
英語で彼らはトルニトスと呼んだ
this is very famous
これはとても有名です
Anyone who does volcanoes and earthquakes knows
火山や地震をやっている人なら誰でも知っています。
Why
なぜ
In Central America just those volcanoes
中米にはまさにそれらの火山があります
They usually see this first when they erupt
彼らは通常、噴火したときに最初にこれを目にします
Seeing this allergy has a volcano erupts
このアレルギーを見ると火山が噴火する
So this turns out to be an indicator of volcanoes in Central America
これは中米の火山の指標であることが判明
but can't say
でも言えない
Taiwan sees this volcanic eruption
台湾は今回の火山噴火を目撃
Because different volcanoes behave differently
火山が異なれば挙動も異なるため
some volcanoes
いくつかの火山
It can be used as a reference, but what we saw on Dalun Mountain
参考にはなりますが、大輪山で見たもの
It does not mean that the volcano is going to erupt, but it means that it is the color of some activities of the volcano
火山が噴火するという意味ではなく、火山の何らかの活動の色であることを意味します。
Then you look at its frequency which is more interesting, it is 2.1, 4.2, 6.3, 8.4
次に、その周波数を見ると、さらに興味深いことがわかります。2.1、4.2、6.3、8.4 です。
It's just a few special multiplier signals
それはほんの数個の特別な乗算信号です
Of course, this is also a ratio, as if you plucked 3 strings on the pipa
もちろんこれも比率であり、まるで琵琶の3本の弦を弾いたようなものです。
Those three different frequencies come out, so there can't be these options underneath.
これら 3 つの異なる周波数が出てくるため、その下にこれらのオプションは存在できません。
The same is when you have an extension to a different column seam at the same time
同時に別の柱継ぎ目に延長がある場合も同様です。
A row of seams is a frequency, B row of seams is a series of seams with a frequency
A 列の縫い目は周波数、B 列の縫い目は周波数を持つ一連の縫い目です
If it is blown at the same time, it will come out with some fixed frequencies when bitten.
同時に吹くと噛まれた時に一定の周波数で出てきます。
There is also this low frequency, in fact its frequency is very low
この低い周波数もあります。実際、その周波数は非常に低いです。
Then this one is also very classic, the eruption of the Pinda Tubo volcano just mentioned
それから、これも非常に古典的なもので、先ほど触れたピンダ トゥボの火山噴火です。
Do it for me on January 17th, at the erupting...
1月17日、噴火の時に私のためにやってください...
in the first ten days or so
最初の10日ほどで
they see these things
彼らはこれらのことを見ます
Hundreds of low-frequency earthquakes came out
低周波地震が何百回も出た
Finally they explained
最後に彼らは説明してくれました
When the magma runs in the cracks of the rock
マグマが岩の割れ目に流れ込むとき
low frequency signal
低周波信号
So this is also a good indicator
これも良い指標です
If Dalinshan we see
大林山が見えたら
a lot of this words
この言葉がたくさん
It's also a big warning sign
それは大きな危険信号でもあります
That also has the Cheung Chau flag
長州旗もあるよ
In fact, there are quite a lot of pigs of this kind.
実際、この種の豚はたくさんいます。
I will speed up a little bit
少しずつスピードアップしていきます
Then let's take what the chairman told us at the time.
では、当時の会長の言葉を聞いてみましょう。
Academician Mr. Li You
学会員李佑氏
Later, he was also the director of our Earth Science Rescue Institute.
その後、彼は地球科学救助研究所の所長も務めました。
After he chaired the committee here
彼がここの委員会の委員長を務めた後、
Then we finish this volcano observatory
それではこの火山展望台を終了します
Of course the mission of the Volcano Observatory
もちろん火山観測所の使命も
mainly volcanic disasters
主に火山災害
But it actually seems to be a negative
でも実際はマイナスな気がする
But there are also positive
しかし、ポジティブな面もあります
this volcanic resource
この火山資源は
Seismic Development
耐震開発
In fact, they are two sides of the same body.
実際、それらは同じ体の表裏の関係にあります。
If we take these magma
このマグマを取ったら
These earthquake surveys are clear
これらの地震調査は明らかです
In fact, it can be applied
実は応用できるんです
Two Yamada Production Axis
山田の2つの生産軸
what is it
それは何ですか
Huo Garden is very beautiful natural landscape
霍園はとても美しい自然景観です
There are also volcanic fumaroles
火山の噴気孔もあります
The hole of exile is a landscape unique to these volcanoes
流刑の穴はこの火山特有の風景です
different time periods
さまざまな期間
Huang Wen during the day
日中の黄温
very beautiful
非常に美しい
These are some photos taken by our TVU colleagues over there
これらは、TVU の同僚が向こうで撮った写真です
It has snowed in the past two years
ここ2年で雪が降りました
It's also very rare
それもとても珍しいです
The snow scene throughout our TVU
TVU全体の雪景色
that hot spring
あの温泉
After these beautiful landscapes
この美しい風景の後に
If in the development of hot springs
温泉開発なら
The development of four
4人の開発
Could provide a better tour
より良いツアーを提供できるかもしれません
An area for leisure
レジャーエリア
Then these are these snow monkeys in Hokkaido, Japan
それから、これらは日本の北海道のスノーモンキーです
they also know
彼らも知っています
Take a hot spring when it's cold
寒い時は温泉に入りましょう
The largest seismic development is the
最大の地震開発は、
is Iceland
アイスランドです
Iceland actually they
アイスランド、実は彼らは
In addition to enjoying these hot springs
これらの温泉を楽しむだけでなく、
They are also the world's geothermal development
それらは世界の地熱開発でもあります
About Iceland's Energy Roughly
アイスランドのエネルギーについてざっくりと
More than 80% are geothermal
80％以上が地熱
So they don't need Henan factory
だから河南省の工場は必要ない
Henan plant does not need to burn coal
河南省の工場は石炭を燃やす必要がない
they enjoy the natural
彼らは自然を楽しんでいます
Since Taiwan has these volcanic geothermal
台湾には火山性地熱があるので、
actually
実際
Conceptually, we should do some work here
概念的には、ここでいくつかの作業を行う必要があります
So will continental volcanoes have geothermal development?
では、大陸の火山でも地熱は発達するのでしょうか？
In addition to volcanic construction
火山建設に加えて
In fact, I also spent some time thinking
実は私も時間をかけて考えました
doing these jobs
これらの仕事をしている
We put up some seismic stations that look like
次のような地震観測所をいくつか設置しました。
There seems to be a big one here
ここに大きいのがありそうだ
Hot discussion storage area
ホットなディスカッションの保管エリア
if science
科学なら
This should be
これはそうあるべきです
Geothermal development should be a good place
地熱開発は良い場所のはずだ
But I don't believe he's in a national park.
でも彼が国立公園にいるとは信じないでください
This environmental protection regulation may also design customer service
この環境保護規制は顧客サービスも設計する可能性があります
but anyway
とにかく
At the level of technology, we can do some related things
テクノロジーのレベルでは、いくつかの関連したことを行うことができます
Well, the map part is more fun
まあ、マップ部分のほうが楽しいけどね
this voice
この声
This is actually the media or something
これは実際にはメディアか何かです
You may also have the impression
という印象もあるかもしれません
After a while, it was said that someone heard a strange sound
しばらくすると、誰かが奇妙な音を聞いたという
That's 15 years
それは15年です
someone heard something
誰かが何かを聞いた
Anyway, some descriptions mean that there is sound
とにかく、いくつかの説明は音があることを意味します
Someone over here heard someone over here
こっちの誰かがこっちの誰かの声を聞いた
In fact, when the media came to ask us
実際、メディアが私たちに質問しに来たとき、
I probably have a score but it wasn't organized well at that time
おそらくスコアはあると思いますが、当時はうまく整理されていませんでした
so just pretend not to know
だから知らないふりをしてください
I probably know it all by now
たぶんもう全部知ってるよ
also in history
歴史の中でも
You see, this is 1835 and 53 years
ほら、これは 1835 年と 53 年です
Three Days of Summer Big Butt Sandwich
夏のデカ尻サンド三日間
it will be very noisy
とても騒がしいでしょう
then we
それから私たち
Since we do these our TBO colleagues
私たちはこれらを行っているので、TBOの同僚
Now I often call and say
今ではよく電話してこう言います
The teacher heard the name of the place this morning
先生は今朝その場所の名前を聞きました
It's just that some people can hear it and some people can't.
ただ聞こえる人もいれば聞こえない人もいるというだけです。
of course
もちろん
some say some don't
言わない人もいる
is there any
何かありますか
we rely on evidence
私たちは証拠に依存します
There are of course many reasons for place names
もちろん地名の由来はいろいろありますが、
There are various other place names with earthquakes
他にも地震のある地名はいろいろあります
Today we're going to talk about the place names of Huo Zhan
今日は霍戦の地名についてお話します。
this is our sacrificial
これは私たちの犠牲です
this is about five minutes long
これは約5分です
But I'd say it's like five seconds or less
でも5秒以内だと思います
The reason is because everyone may fall asleep after listening to it for five minutes.
理由は、5分も聴けば誰でも眠ってしまう可能性があるからです。
The first reason is that if five minutes ago
1 つ目の理由は、5 分前であれば
In fact, its frequency is very low
実はその頻度は非常に低いのです
you can't hear
聞こえません
Because our ears are from 20Hz to 20,000Hz
私たちの耳の周波数は 20Hz から 20,000Hz であるため、
normal person
正常人
If it is 10Hz
10Hzであれば
we can't hear
私たちには聞こえません
just too low frequency
ただ周波数が低すぎる
or too high frequency
または周波数が高すぎる
So for everyone to hear
だからみんなに聞いてもらえるように
I call it a little time-lapse sound
ちょっとしたタイムラプスサウンドと呼んでいます
turn five minutes into five seconds
5分を5秒に変える
this is overclocking
これはオーバークロックです
But the five flavors are just like a plane flying past
でも5つの味はまるで飛行機が通り過ぎていくようだ
But this we based on these signals
しかし、これはこれらの信号に基づいています
actually you see
実際に見てください
This is a different kind of earthquake warfare
これは別の種類の地震戦です
Why Earthquake Warfare Receives Sound
なぜ地震戦が響き渡るのか
In fact, the sound is the vibration of air
実は音は空気の振動なのです
air shaken to the surface
空気が表面に揺れる
our ruins on the surface
地上の私たちの遺跡
Shake our relics too
私たちの遺物も振ってください
Because shaking the ground shakes the ruins
地面が揺れると遺跡も揺れるから
relics will shake holes
遺物が穴を揺るがす
So let's take these cases into account
では、これらのケースを考慮してみましょう
Then these earthquake shadows we can see
それから私たちが見ることができるこれらの地震の影
You see this is every earthquake video received
これが受信したすべての地震ビデオです
Then we according to its sequence
次に、その順序に従って
we can go and find out where it is
私たちは行ってそれがどこにあるかを見つけることができます
For example, we found it in a small oil pit
たとえば、小さな石油ピットで見つけました。
very clear
非常に明確な
I don't know if it's here or here
ここなのかここなのか分からない
About 10 meters to 50 meters
10メートルから50メートルくらい
But it won't go outside the small oil pit
でも小さなオイルピットからは出られない
Anyway, it's here in three minutes
とにかく、3分以内に到着します
very sure
非常確定
This is just about one hundred and two minutes
ここまではちょうど 102 分ほどです
I put it like two seconds
2秒くらい置いた
you will hear
聞くでしょう
Actually, look carefully at this
実はこれをよく見てください
This picture alone is enough to write an article
この写真だけで記事が書ける
This, this, this scientific international article
これ、これ、この国際科学論文
I will discuss this
これについて話し合います
this is time
これは時間です
this is the frequency
これが周波数です
This is when the whole thing explodes
これはイメージ全体が爆発するときです
Then before it explodes it has frequency from
そして、爆発する前に、次の周波数があります。
70Hz has been adjusted to almost 40Hz
70Hzをほぼ40Hzに調整しました
The frequency is always deactivated and then detonated
周波数は常に無効化され、その後爆発します。
In fact, there is a very simple description, just like playing that heavy sky cannon when I was a child
実はとても簡単な説明があり、子供の頃にあの重い空砲を遊んでいたようなものです。
You chirp at one point and it explodes in the sky
ある時点で鳴くと、それは空で爆発します
That's certainly not a heavy sky cannon
それは決して重い空砲ではありません
This actually has good physics behind it
これには実際に優れた物理学が裏付けられています
We probably don't have time to talk about deeper things
もっと深いことについて話す時間はおそらくないでしょう
Xiaoerkeng is actually
実は小爾坑は
These things are often recorded
こういったことはよく記録されています
That child's pit is more interesting
あの子のピットの方が面白い
This is the location of the children's pit
児童ピットの場所はこちら
You climbed up to Qiqisan in Xiaoerkeng
小爾坑の七岐山に登りました
this is the trail
これが道です
You can see these little pits along the trail
トレイル沿いに小さな穴が見えます
Then it actually becomes a series of cracks
そして実際につながって一連の亀裂ができた
How did these cracks come about?
この亀裂はどのようにして生じたのでしょうか?
In fact, I know where these place names come from.
実は私はこれらの地名の由来を知っています。
Actually this is every
実はこれは毎度のことです
Just now the one that exploded like a heavy sky cannon
たった今、重天砲のように爆発したのが
result
結果
mean to say
言う意味
Of course, this small hole was not dropped when it rained.
もちろん、この小さな穴は雨が降ったときに落ちたものではありません。
In turn it is a gas explosion from within
今度は内部からのガス爆発です
It's when there's a lot of pressure underneath
根底に大きなプレッシャーがかかっているときです
it explodes instantly
それはすぐに爆発します
It's a hole when it explodes
爆発すると穴が開く
so it goes along this fault line
つまりこの断層線に沿って進むのです
just a hole a hole a hole
ただの穴、穴、穴
It's just that the geological age has been exploding.
地質時代が爆発的に進んでいるというだけです。
That's how it flows on the surface
表面的にはそうやって流れてるんだよ
Then if you briefly show the entire fracture hole
次に、骨折穴全体を簡単に示すと、
These are all one by one
これらはすべて一つ一つです
It seems that these pits are connected when it rains
雨が降ると穴が繋がるようです
very very many
非常非常多
The rep says it's actually been active
担当者は実際に活動していると言っています
It's just that we haven't paid attention to it
ただ私たちがそれに気づいていないだけなのです
Generally speaking, when we talk about volcanic eruptions, it is flames that come out.
一般的に火山の噴火といえば、出てくるのは炎です。
That like this steam explosion just wanted to look like
この水蒸気爆発のようなものが見たかっただけです
That's the sound of that explosion
それがあの爆発音です
That's like Hawaii
ハワイみたいですね
Or a lot of it is the flame plasma to the surface
あるいは、その多くは地表への炎プラズマです
There are lava flows and broken cave flows
溶岩流と壊れた洞窟の流れがあります
what is this one
これは何ですか
It's just like Kaohsiung gas explosion
高雄のガス爆発みたいだ
exploded
爆発した
only this
これだけ
That's why we can burn the pot and blow it up to gain strength
だからこそ、私たちは力を得るために鍋を燃やし、爆破することができます
Then don't say it doesn't seem threatening.
それなら、脅威ではないとは言わないでください。
On January 3, 2014, he was an explosive
2014年1月3日、彼は爆​​発物だった。
He also caused the deaths of more than 60 people
彼はまた60人以上の死者を出した
That death is really unfortunate
その死は本当に残念だ
it's autumn and it's noon
秋だ、そして正午だ
then he is saturday
それから彼は土曜日です
Because this January 3rd is like our neutral mountains
この1月3日は私たちの中立の山のようなものだから
Usually no one lives nearby
普段は近くに誰も住んでいない
But the autumn wind is also super beautiful
でも秋風もすごく綺麗ですよ
A group of people went hiking on Saturday
人々のグループは土曜日にハイキングに行きました
Then when I ran to the top of the mountain
それから山の頂上まで走ったとき
Their habit is when they reach the top of the mountain
彼らの習慣は山の頂上に着いたときです
reach the top of the mountain before noon
正午前に山の頂上に到着する
Come down for a crispy or bento
クリスピーやお弁当を食べに来てください
So it's almost noon and everybody's at the top of the mountain
正午近くになり、全員が山の頂上に到着しました
As a result, the explosion at that time
その結果、その時の爆発は、
That's why six or seventy
だから6か70
if it's monday or three o'clock in the afternoon
月曜日か午後3時なら
a cat is fine
猫は大丈夫です
it's such an unfortunate thing
それはとても残念なことです
this is every day
これは毎日です
This is Yang Mingzhang, we counted
こちらはヤン・ミンジャンです、私たちは数えました
because it sounds like a bird
鳥のような鳴き声なので
is still in the woods
まだ森の中にいます
this one is a little longer
これは少し長いです
about two minutes
約2分
In fact, I have collected a lot of these
実は、これをたくさん集めたんです
no i can't listen
いいえ、聞こえません
This is like a train
これは電車のようです
played the sound of a train
電車の音を鳴らした
This is like a giant tree
これは巨大な木のようなものです
that's good
それは良い
Then this giant tree just now
すると今この巨大な木が
Actually, I'm going to write another article
実はまた別の記事を書こうと思っています
Let's just talk about it. It's a volcano conversation.
ちょっと話しましょう、火山の話です。
In fact, it is one by one
実は一つ一つです
This jet tube happens and the other is this one
このジェットチューブは発生し、もう1つはこれです
So A and B are over there
AとBはあそこにいるよ
sing together
一緒に歌う
super interesting
超興味深い
It's the dialogue of the volcano
それは火山の対話です
Then this is Zhongshan Luo and Ziping after spraying
これがスプレー後の中山羅と紫平です
Then it's like the two are talking
そしたら二人で話してるようだった
The last one is
最後は
It was an accident that the dean of Guoyun
国雲学部長が事故に遭ったのは偶然だった
I'll skip it first
最初はスキップします
That's the sound of Dean Guoyun seeing my volcanoes
それは、ディーン・グオユンが私の火山を見ている音です
He went to the Academy of Performing Arts
彼は舞台芸術アカデミーに通いました
He said this voice can be used as background
この声は背景として使えるとのこと
they played for two hours
彼らは2時間遊んだ
Just those pictures over there
そこにある写真だけ
I'm going to listen to this kind of wow, this is really exciting
こういうのを聴いてみます、すごいですね、これは。
This is the combination of science and humanities
これは科学と人文科学の組み合わせです
final volcano heartbeat
最後の火山の鼓動
Seismic.com has recorded many earthquakes
Seismic.com は多くの地震を記録しています
nothing special
特にない
But the funny thing is that we are here in Dayoukeng
しかし面白いのは、私たちがここ大油坑にいるということです。
remember hundreds of earthquakes
何百もの地震を思い出してください
What's so special about this earthquake?
この地震の何がそんなに特別なのでしょうか？
This is the new electrogram
これが新しい電気記録図です
Every black line here is
ここのすべての黒い線は
This one is an earthquake station
ここは地震観測所です
Every earthquake also has a
すべての地震には、
just an earthquake
ただの地震
So when an earthquake occurs
それで、地震が起きたとき、
For all stations received
受信した全局について
This one bar after another is an earthquake
この1バー1バーが地震です
For example, if I look at a single one, it's fine.
たとえば、1つを見てみると、
single station you see
あなたが見る単一の駅
When each vertical bar
それぞれの縦棒が
just a small earthquake
ほんの小さな地震
Then this small earthquake turned out to be periodic
その後、この小さな地震は周期的であることが判明しました
Hualien Earthquake
花蓮地震
probably no one can understand
おそらく誰も理解できないでしょう
when will the next earthquake occur
次の地震はいつ起こりますか
But I'm here to tell you
でも、私はあなたに伝えるためにここにいます
Now there's another 18 minutes
あと18分ある
in 18 minutes
18分以内に
do statistics here
ここで統計を行う
Of course not, it's just a few seconds off.
もちろん違います、ほんの数秒の違いです。
There will be one in these 18 or 19 minutes
この 18 分か 19 分以内に 1 つあります
This is about 1, 200 earthquakes
これは約1,200回の地震に相当します
every 18 minutes
18分ごと
We know our new tickets are
新しいチケットは
Seventy to eighty beats per minute
1分間に70～80拍
But you count this 18 minutes
でも、この 18 分を数えてください
Seventy or eighty times a day
1日に70回も80回も
means he dances very slowly
つまり彼はとてもゆっくりと踊っている
But it's more interesting to say when this heartbeat started
しかし、この心拍がいつ始まったかを言うのはもっと興味深いです
He is from a 4.8 earthquake in Hualien
彼は花蓮で起きたマグニチュード4.8の地震の被害者です。
When the earthquake wave reaches Yangmingshan
地震波が陽明山に到達したとき
heartbeat starts beating
心臓の鼓動が鼓動し始める
He's not Moby
彼はモービーじゃない
He looks like someone is going to wake him up and bite him
誰かが彼を起こして噛みつきそうだ
It's time for a heartbeat
心臓の鼓動の時間です
This is another Taichung earthquake
これまた台中地震です
3.7 As soon as the earthquake came, Bobobo's heartbeat came
3.7 地震が来るとすぐにボーボボの鼓動が来た
it happened three times
それは3回起こりました
Although there were three times I was super excited
3回もあったけど超興奮した
Earthquakes are periodic
地震は周期的です
This is something I've never heard of in the whole world
こんなことは世の中で聞いたことがない
then i will make a metaphor
それから私は比喩をします
normal heartbeat
正常な心拍
Then there is a problem with the image
それから画像に問題があります
Start trimmer, start jumping wildly, stop jumping after jumping
トリマーを開始、激しくジャンプを開始、ジャンプ後にジャンプを停止
then jump again
それからまたジャンプする
Then sent to the hospital, of course the electric shock
その後病院に送られ、当然電気ショックを受けました
Shock again jump jump jump jump up
ショック再びジャンプジャンプジャンプジャンプアップ
So the Hualien earthquake Taichung reporter seemed to be telegraphed
それで花蓮地震台中記者が電報されたようです
So Yang Mingshan may have fallen asleep
つまり陽明山は眠ってしまったのかもしれない
It's just a new dance. I haven't danced for a long time.
長い間踊っていないので、新しいダンスです。
The earthquake shocked him and made him start jumping
地震が彼に衝撃を与え、飛び跳ね始めた
But it's a metaphor, not a real thing
でもそれは比喩であって現実のものではない
a fun thing
楽しいこと
It's this new jump that kills
命を奪うのはこの新しいジャンプだ
Animal Xiao Laozi jumped hundreds of times
動物の小老子は何百回もジャンプしました
his life is short
彼の人生は短い
Elephants are good at jumping very slowly
ゾウはゆっくりとジャンプするのが得意です
then live longer
それから長生きしてください
Of course that man is no longer an animal.
もちろん、その男はもはや動物ではありません。
Humans are no longer ordinary animals
人間はもはや普通の動物ではない
This quote means
この引用の意味は、
Anyway, the faster the new jump, the shorter the life
とにかく、新しいジャンプが速いほど寿命は短くなります
Well if this extends it to volcanoes
これを火山にまで拡張すると
In those 18 minutes, he danced super slow and super slow
その18分間、彼は超スロー、超スローで踊りました。
so he can live a long time
そうすれば彼は長生きできる
I'm unscientific
私は非科学的です
a bit silly
ちょっとばかげた
that last summary
その最後の要約
we're back at mainland mountain
私たちは本土の山に戻ってきました
cooperate with this health committee
この保健委員会に協力する
Metropolis and Old Town of Taipei
台北の大都市と旧市街
Taipei City is a city of millions of people
台北市は何百万もの人口が住む都市です
Of course Vesuvius, Pompeii, has 20,000 people
もちろん、ポンペイのヴェスヴィオには2万人が住んでいます
This is much worse
これはさらに悪いことです
That's about 10 kilometers away.
それは約10キロメートル離れています。
are very similar distances
非常に似た距離です
that is volcanic
それは火山です
The continent's volcanoes
大陸の火山
This date may be 6000 years
この日付は6000年前かもしれない
But Vesuvius actually sprayed it again in 1914
しかし、ベスビオ火山は実際に 1914 年に再び噴霧しました。
The height of Seven Star Mountain and Vesuvi is actually over a thousand
七星山とベスビの高さはどちらも千を超えます
That's mainly interesting
それは主に興味深いことです
The area of ​​our magma chamber is about 70 square kilometers
私たちのマグマだまりの面積は約70平方キロメートルです
Vesuvius probably
おそらくヴェスヴィオ山
actually bigger
実際はもっと大きい
6, 7 times
6、7倍
6 times is actually bigger
実際は6倍のほうが大きい
The top of the volcanic block is relatively large
火山塊頂比較大
The depth is relatively shallow
深さは比較的浅いです
So we go a little deeper
それで、もう少し深く進んでいきます
deeper
もっと深く
but
しかし
We are now trying to find out if there is a 5km or 10km
私たちは今、5kmか10kmかどうか調べようとしています。
Magma reservoir
マグマだまり
then this is us
それならこれが私たちです
work in recent years
近年の仕事
history in the sea of ​​course this
海の歴史はもちろんこれ
The side is also terrible
横もひどいよ
Yangmingshan no
陽明山なし
The last one is what we want to convey today
最後は今日伝えたいこと
Whether it's a big volcano or a small volcano
大きな火山でも小さな火山でも
Population nearby or far away
近隣または遠方の人口
In fact, in the past, science can tell us
実際、過去には科学が私たちに教えてくれました。
you just do monitoring
あなたはモニタリングをするだけです
very easy thing
とても簡単なこと
There is probably a considerable degree of protection
おそらくかなりの保護力があると思われます
Monitoring is a simple matter in terms of science
モニタリングは科学的には簡単なことです
You just put the instrument down and do some analysis
機器を置いて分析を行うだけです
and then probably give us some
そしておそらく私たちに何かをくれるでしょう
good reference instrument
良いリファレンス機器
The ancient city of Weishuwei is here
古代都市魏州衛はここにあります
But Napoli so they keep doing it
しかし、ナポリはそれを続ける
This is a volcanic city
ここは火山都市です
cities on or around volcanoes
火山の上またはその周囲の都市
Taipei is also one of the volcano cities
台北も火山都市の一つです
the problem is that
問題はそれです
Will the volcano move?
火山は動くでしょうか？
we do not know
我々は知りません
but we have to be prepared
しかし、私たちは準備をしなければなりません
if one day it moves
いつかそれが動くなら
we need to know in advance
事前に知っておく必要があります
That's the job of the Big Volcano Spectator Station
それがビッグ ボルケーノ スペクテーター ステーションの仕事です
so simple question
とても単純な質問
I am often asked by many people
いろんな人からよく聞かれるんですが
So maybe now you guys can answer
それで、もう答えられるかもしれません
Will the first one be active again? Yes
最初のものは再びアクティブになりますか? はい
I usually don't dare to speak
普段はあえて話さないのですが
I usually want to say that it cannot be ruled out
通常、それは排除できないと言いたいのですが、
more like this
もっとこのように
And the second question is, will spending money be attractive? Yes
2 番目の質問は、お金を使うことが魅力的かどうかということです? はい。
everyone trust me
みんな私を信頼してる
I often give speeches here and there and tell people that's what I say
私はよくあちこちでスピーチをして、人々にこう言います。
But actually I'm pretty stressed when I go home
でも実際は家に帰るとかなりストレスになるんです
Where did it come from? A volcanic eruption
どこから来たの? 火山の噴火
I still haven't told everyone that I might
私はまだみんなにそうするかもしれないことを伝えていない
may have to kill himself
自殺しなければならないかもしれない
And where did the millions of citizens flee to?
そして何百万もの国民はどこへ逃げたのでしょうか？
This is the section chief of the Taipei exercise
こちらは台北演習の課長です
been looking up i mean
調べているということは
What should I do? What should Mr. Lin do?
私はどうしたらいいですか? リンさんはどうしたらいいですか?
He said where are our six million people going?
彼は、我が国の600万人はどこへ行くのか、と言いました。
I said don't scare yourself
怖がらないでって言った
There is no such thing as six million people, right?
600万人なんて存在しないですよね？
That Qiandu also wanted to say that we will move to Taichung.
その千都も台中に移動すると言いたかったのです。
The last question has an answer
最後の質問には答えがあります
We should not be the ancient city of Pangbei
私たちは古代都市龐北であってはなりません
In addition to many natural conditions
多くの自然条件に加えて、
what is the most important
最も重要なことは何ですか
Time and space are different, right?
時間と空間は違いますよね？
2000 years ago there was no science
2000年前には科学は存在しなかった
people don't know what's going on
人々は何が起こっているのか分かりません
but we now have science
しかし今では科学があります
Science can tell us many answers
科学は多くの答えを教えてくれます
So the simple answer is no
したがって、単純な答えはノーです
so this is the festival
だからこれはお祭りです
just want us to be with the volcano
ただ火山と一緒にいたいだけなの
Coexistence king but through science
科学による共存王
Finally, I would like to thank the relevant units
最後に、関係各所に感謝の意を表したいと思います。
Because this plan has actually been in the works for more than ten years.
なぜなら、この計画は実は10年以上も前から進められていたからです。
It's this big plan that has been in the works for more than ten years.
この大規模な計画は 10 年以上にわたって進められてきました。
The process is not a single
プロセスは単一ではありません
this this department
この部門
or Chinese
または中国語
can pay for all this
これらすべてを支払うことができます
So we use various channels
そのため、さまざまなチャネルを使用します
and then go to convince people
それから人々を説得しに行きます
give money to people
人々にお金を与える
So let's build this volcano-official battle
だから、この火山公式の戦いを構築しましょう
ok this took a while
わかりました、これには時間がかかりました
Very sorry
本当にごめんなさい
Thanks
ありがとう
Well, we thank Researcher Lin for a very good presentation.
リン研究員の素晴らしいプレゼンテーションに感謝いたします。
Now the rest of our time is open to questions
残りの時間は質疑応答です
We have prepared exquisite gifts on site
素敵なプレゼントをその場でご用意しております
hand over here
ここに渡してください
We have ten, so the first ten
10 個あるので、最初の 10 個
If the first ten people ask questions, they will get a small gift
先着10名様に質問すると粗品をプレゼント
There's that microphone in front of you guys
皆さんの前にマイクがあります
wait a minute for a question
聞きたいならちょっと待ってください
please use the microphone
マイクを使ってください
Click on a green part
緑色の部分をクリックしてください
This will turn the microphone on
これによりマイクがオンになります
now what's your question
さて、質問は何ですか
here
ここ
Hello Mr. Lin
こんにちは、リンさん
ok actually what i want to ask is
わかりました、実際に私が聞きたいのは
If an alert occurs
アラートが発生した場合
There will be a volcanic eruption in the next ten days
今後10日以内に火山の噴火が起こるでしょう
no results
検索結果はありません
seems more serious
もっと深刻なようです
It's like a typhoon is coming, and it's a holiday
台風が来ているようで、休日です。
No, my question is actually
いいえ、私の質問は実際には
The characteristics of Tatun Volcano are different from other volcanoes
大屯火山の特徴は他の火山とは異なります
For example, are the volcanoes in Hawaii different?
たとえば、ハワイの火山は違うのでしょうか？
In other words, just ten days ago
つまり、ちょうど10日前に
That dense vibration thing
あの濃密な振動のこと
In fact, I have no way to prove the Datun Volcano
実際のところ、大屯火山を証明する方法はありません。
Really like that, time really explodes in the future
ほんとにそんなふうに 時間が本当に爆発する未来
unless it really explodes
本当に爆発しない限り
Then this experience comes from the situation of the volcano in Hawaii
そして、この経験はハワイの火山の状況から来ています
Will they be the same
それらは同じでしょうか
still may be different thanks
まだ違うかもしれません、ありがとう
this is a very good question
これはとても良い質問です
and you're an insider
そしてあなたはインサイダーです
Volcanic outbreaks are not 100%
火山噴火は100%ではない
And every volcano behaves differently
そして、火山ごとに挙動が異なります
In fact, the Hawaiian volcano and Mount Fuji
実はハワイの火山と富士山は
Or that there are actually many types of volcanoes
あるいは、実際には多くの種類の火山があるということ
Hawaii is relatively annual magma
ハワイは比較的毎年マグマが発生する
so it just won't explode
だから爆発しないだけ
This one was blasted
こいつは爆破された
It actually flows more like water
実際は水のように流れます
That's like this volcano in the Pacific Rim
それは環太平洋の火山のようなものです
it will explode like
みたいに爆発するだろう
That's because of its annual consistency
それは毎年の一貫性があるからです
Or we say its acid-base scientifically
または、科学的には酸塩基と言います。
Its ratio of that SIO2
そのSIO2の比率
you can imagine that
それは想像できます
as a pot of water
水の入ったポットとして
rain is like a pot of water
雨は水の入った鍋のようなもの
when you heat it up the water boils
加熱すると水が沸騰します
But if you cook a pot of porridge
しかし、鍋でお粥を調理すると、
or corn chowder with words
または言葉付きのコーンチャウダー
when the viscosity is high
粘度が高い場合
as soon as you boil it it will
沸騰させるとすぐに出来上がります
it will
そうなる
pop
ポップ
right
右
it's sticky
ベタベタしている
it keeps accumulating energy
エネルギーを蓄積し続ける
energy
エネルギー
then it's about to explode
それから爆発寸前です
so different volcanoes
とても違う火山
In fact, its composition is different
実は成分が違うんです
it behaves differently
それは動作が異なります
So we can't put
だから入れられない
Xia Yao Pooh or usual Toubot
Xia Yao Poohまたは通常のToubot
or any volcanic act to bring
またはもたらす火山活動
Predicting what will happen to our big volcanoes
私たちの大きな火山に何が起こるかを予測する
In fact, it is everyone
実はみんなそうなんです
or each volcano
またはそれぞれの火山
has its own unique personality
独自の個性を持っています
So we want to predict the behavior of a person
そこで人の行動を予測したいのです
We can't put people in A
Aに人を入れることはできない
past to predict B's
B を予測するための過去
In fact, the risk is great
実はリスクが大きい
we better be
私たちはそうなったほうがいい
Make a good observation and understanding of A
Aをよく観察して理解する
See how it behaves
どのように動作するかを見てください
Then we make predictions based on this
次に、以下に基づいて予測を立てます。
but even so
しかしそれでも
we can't
できません
Actually there are
実際にはあります
Several volcanoes have said that they think they will erupt.
いくつかの火山は、噴火する可能性があると述べている。
This is sometimes because of a very simple reason
これは非常に単純な理由による場合があります
Your magma keeps going up and down, and your successor is unreasonable
君のマグマは上がったり下がったりを繰り返し、君の継承は理不尽だ
In fact, Mount Fuji used to be this year in 2001.
実は、2001年には富士山がありました。
Japanese scientists are extremely nervous with the government
日本の科学者は政府に対して極度に神経質になっている
Why did they keep running from 20 kilometers away from the earthquake
なぜ彼らは地震から20キロ離れたところから逃げ続けたのか
After running 2 kilometers, he thought he might come up tomorrow or the day after tomorrow.
2キロ走った後、彼は明日か明後日には登れるだろうと思った
be quiet from now on
これからは静かにしてください
So this is still his
つまり、これはまだ彼のものです
With this uncertainty, we can only do our best
この不確実性の中で、私たちは最善を尽くすことしかできません
Hello teacher, what I want to ask is
こんにちは、先生、聞きたいのは
It's the shadow of the S wave you mentioned earlier
先ほどのS波の影です。
There is also P-wave's smoke call, which is the place where smoke call arrives
P-waveのスモークコールもあり、スモークコールが届く場所です
These two phenomena, these two phenomena are what I just said from the teacher.
この二つの現象、この二つの現象は今先生から申し上げたとおりでございます。
I think all I know is that he reflects
私が知っているのは、彼が反省しているということだけだと思う
He represents the existence of liquid substances under the ground
地下に液体物質が存在することを表現している
Then how can we infer from the existence of this substance
では、この物質の存在からどのように推測できるのでしょうか。
It is possible to estimate the volume of the magma reservoir and
マグマだまりの体積を推定することができ、
Is it the depth of these queries Thanks
これらの質問は奥深いものですか、ありがとう
The volume is calculated according to the surface of our land
体積は土地の表面に基づいて計算されます
yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
We can probably heat up a range
おそらくレンジを加熱できるでしょう
that depth is a good question
その深さは良い質問です
Depth because of more scientific issues
より科学的な問題による深み
That is to say, I didn't talk much here.
つまり、ここではあまり話さなかったのですが、
That is to say, I use earthquakes at different depths for cross-comparison
つまり、相互比較のために異なる深さの地震を使用します。
There is a little bit of this depth past and this depth
この深さの過去とこの深さは少しだけあります
If cut to yes or no
「はい」または「いいえ」にカットされた場合
That is, it has an angle, right?
つまり角度があるということですよね？
If at the very surface it doesn't have both
表面的には両方を持っていない場合
If it's 10 kilometers maybe it starts a little bit on this side and this side
10キロならこっち側とこちら側から少しずつ始まるかも
there is a gap
ギャップがあります
So take it slow
だからゆっくりしてください
But this is just a rough estimate
しかし、これはあくまでも概算です
That's why we have our second big plan.
だからこそ私たちは第二の大きな計画を立てています。
Hope to make more accurate
より正確になることを願っています
So something like this
それで、このようなもの
At present, the preliminary results can only reach this
現時点では、暫定結果はこれまでしか到達できません
To make his relationship with that family from four angles
あの家族との関係を4つの角度からみる
Because of this probably in the whole world I think I'm the first to do this
おそらく全世界でこれをやったのは私が初めてだと思います
Because, for example, Mt. Fuji, theirs, or Mount Aso
なぜなら、例えば、富士山や彼らの富士山、あるいは阿蘇山だからです。
They are very clear about the evidence of Yeonjangku
彼らはヨンジャンクの証拠について非常に明確です
people don't need to do this
人々はこれを行う必要はありません
That's because it's too controversial in Taiwan
台湾では物議を醸しすぎているから
We can't see that thing on the surface
私たちはそれを表面上では見ることができません
That's why I worked so hard to come up with a way to verify it.
だからこそ、私はそれを検証する方法を考え出すために一生懸命働きました。
So this should be the only
したがって、これが唯一のはずです
The only scientifically I know of anyone doing this
科学的に私がこれを行っている人を知っている唯一の人物
yes
はい
Hello Mr. Lin
こんにちは、リンさん
I want to ask is in the past geological records
聞きたいのは過去の地質記録です
Is the Datong volcanic group like that?
大同火山群もそんな感じでしょうか？
Is there a record of such spontaneous pyroclastic activity at Yunhyen Volcano?
雲玄火山でそのような自然火砕活動の記録はあるのでしょうか?
In history, in our human history, there is no
歴史の中で、私たちの人類の歴史の中で、
But in geology
しかし地質学では
If you're interested, I can show you the trail where the debris flows
興味があれば、土石流の跡をお見せします
what's that called
それは何と呼ばれますか
There are several places where there are debris streams on the road.
道路上に土石流が発生している箇所が数か所あります。
We haven't ordered that one yet
私たちはまだそれを注文していません
We're just like 6,000 years now, just a volcanic ash date
私たちは今から 6,000 年前のような、単なる火山灰の時代です
The dating on the other side of the debris flow has not been overcome
土石流の向こう側の年代測定は克服されていない
But at least there's evidence out there
しかし少なくとも証拠はある
is visible from the surface
表面から見える
So I'm not sure if it's possible to be as serious as the suicide in Japan
だから、日本の自殺ほど深刻なことが起こり得るかどうかはわからない
Are you sure you know there is such a record?
そんな記録があるのをご存知ですか？
There is this record, but the history of our humanity is
こんな記録がありますが、私たち人類の歴史は
In Taiwan, it is only possible that there will be no such records in a thousand years or more
台湾では千年以上はそのような記録がなくなる可能性しかない
ok thank you teacher
わかりました、先生ありがとう
Hello teacher
こんにちは先生
Invite that Datong Volcanic Group because his age is quite old
年齢がかなり高いのでチェイス火山グループを招待する
there are two thousand
二千人います
More than 8 million to 200,000
800万以上20万まで
Recently, it was just about 50 million
最近は5000万くらいだった
around 5000 years
5000年左右
So the distribution of a magma chamber in this place
この場所のマグマだまりの分布
From a historical point of view, should it be centralized?
歴史的な観点から見ると、中央集権化すべきでしょうか?
because when it's about to spray flowers
なぜなら、花を散布しようとしているときだからです。
There must be cracks sucked out
吸い出された亀裂があるはずです
right
右
In the period of Big Butt Foshan in Triangular Broken City
大きなヒップの時代、仏山市の三角形の壊れた都市
Is it possible that there will be cracking and sucking out?
ひび割れや吸い込みが出てくる可能性はありますか？
The volume of possible magma chambers relative to
考えられるマグマだまりの体積と相対的な関係
There must also be a match with the split suction
スプリットサクションとのマッチングも必要です
So when it comes to spraying flowers
それで、花にスプレーするときは
Is there one of these two
この2つのうちどちらかはありますか
a proof
証明
yes
はい
Now many academic circles or our experts
現在、多くの学界または当社の専門家が
probably think it is
おそらくそうだと思う
The current triangular city
現在の三角都市
It's actually a crack
実は亀裂なんです
The magma is likely to be on this fissure
マグマはこの亀裂の上にある可能性があります
this run up
この助走
It is along this line of development
この発展の流れに沿っています
In fact, we are not sure about the future.
実際、将来についてはわかりません。
But the possibility is possible
でも可能性はあり得る
So on this trend along the triangular fault
ということで、三角断層に沿ったこの傾向について
Seven Seven Three is right next to the Triangle Fault
七七三は三角断層のすぐ隣にあります
The big oil pit is not far away
大きな石油ピットは遠くない
We saw that seismic activity
私たちはその地震活動を見ました
As far as the seismic activity is concerned, it is on the side of the Seven Seventh Three Oil Pit.
地震活動に関する限り、それはセブン・セブンス・スリー石油ピットの側にあります。
It seems to be quite consistent with the geometry of the triangular fault.
それは三角断層の形状とかなり一致しているようです。
So it's very likely along the fault knee of the Triangular Fault
したがって、三角断層の断層膝に沿っている可能性が非常に高いです。
Yan will come up
ヤンが出てくる
This is guesswork
これは推測です
There is one and another inference that says
次のような推論があります。
because the triangular fault it belongs to a
三角断層に属するため、
Only one thing on the earthquake fault will have a cracked knee
地震断層上で膝にひびが入るのは 1 つだけです
Yeah
うん
so many years till now
今まで何年も
200,000 years to the last 50 million years
20万年から過去5000万年まで
Because it is time in the crust to the geology
地殻から地質への時代だから
is it going to stabilize
安定するのかな
or there will be signs of activity
あるいは活動の兆候があるだろう
Research says there is a comparison problem with the magma chamber
研究によるとマグマだまりとの比較に問題がある
Because if the magma chamber is on the other side
マグマだまりが向こう側にあるなら
There can't be a problem with spraying at this end either.
この端でのスプレーも問題ありません。
Yes, this is actually a good question, that is
はい、これは実際には良い質問です。
because of how we do research now
現在の研究方法のせいで
mostly now
ほとんど今
Then you have to compare with the past
じゃあ過去と比較すればいいのに
to know whether it is regionally stable or regionally unstable
地域的に安定しているか、地域的に不安定であるかを知るため
But the past evidence is actually super vague.
しかし、過去の証拠は実際には非常に曖昧です。
So we just can't compare
だから単純に比較することはできない
So many people say that the magma is in the process of cooling
マグマは冷却の過程にあると多くの人が言っています
Then of course nothing will happen in the future
それなら当然今後何も起こらない
not cooling but warming
冷却ではなく温暖化
Then we don't have good evidence to control this
それでは、これを制御するための十分な証拠はありません
It is now moving up and down
今は上下に動いています
yes yes yes of course
はい、はい、もちろんです
Because of the triangular triple island
三角形のトリプルアイランドなので
Yes Yes Yes
はいはいはい
There is still a lot of work to be done in this aftermath.
この後劇にはまだやるべきことがたくさんあります。
Thanks
ありがとう
Hello Professor Li
こんにちは、李先生
two questions
2つの質問
The first one is like our landslides
最初のものは私たちの地滑りのようなものです
When we all have to issue alerts
全員が警報を発する必要があるとき
Yellow alert when rainfall exceeds how much
降雨量がどれくらいを超えると黄色の警告
Or the amount of rainfall exceeds the red alert
または、降雨量が赤色警報を超えている場合
Don't know about our TVO
TVOについて知りません
Is there any data now
今はデータあるのかな
when the earthquake exceeds how much
地震がどのくらいを超えるとき
or how much the ground temperature exceeds
または地面の温度がどれくらいを超えるか
or when the concentration of carbon dioxide reaches
または二酸化炭素濃度が以下に達したとき
we're going to issue an alert
警報を発令します
We live right under the cape of the volcano
私たちは火山の岬の真下に住んでいます
we care about that
私たちはそれを気にしています
In addition, the second problem is the small travel pit
さらに、2番目の問題は小さなトラベルピットです。
We now call him to the mouth of the mouth
私たちは今、彼を口に呼びます
he didn't stand in burst
彼はバーストに耐えられなかった
Let's call him a blowout
彼を爆発者と呼びましょう
Or call him Collapsing Fire
あるいは、彼を「崩壊する火」と呼んでください
would be more appropriate
より適切でしょう
First the second question should be the burst hole
まず 2 番目の質問はバーストホールでなければなりません
because ben he actually
なぜなら、ベンは実際に
because most of them think
なぜなら彼らのほとんどはそう思っているからです
He's a breach in a fault zone
彼は断層帯の侵害者だ
that ben his behavior is not like that
ベンの行動はそんなものではない
ben he just offline
ベン、彼はちょうどオフラインです
but he is a concave whole
しかし彼は全体的に凹んでいる
like a pit
穴のような
So it's not the same as his line
だからそれは彼のラインと同じではない
he is a blast
彼は最高だ
so we have a lot to contend with
だから私たちは闘わなければならないことがたくさんある
jet
ジェット
the first question is
最初の質問は
vigilance
警戒
very difficult
非常に難しい
But NCDR is the center of the national battlefield
しかし、NCDRは全国的な戦場の中心です
or the Executive Yuan or something like that
あるいは行政院かそのようなもの
Forces me to talk about this every day
毎日このことについて話すよう強制される
But I'm here to be honest
でも、正直に言うとここにいます
Actually, I know very little
実は私もほとんど知識がありません
But the people or the government need a standard
しかし、国民や政府には基準が必要です
So what we are forced to do is a
したがって、私たちがやらなければならないことは、
We try to have no history, no context
私たちは歴史や文脈を持たないように努めています
So we don't know how crazy this volcano is before it erupts
つまり、この火山が噴火する前にどれほど狂っているのかはわかりません
If it has previous records we can probably use it as a reference
過去の記録があれば参考にできるかもしれません
But we don't have any record of this
しかし、私たちにはこれに関する記録がありません
So we can only put the compulsive ones on the other volcanoes
したがって、他の火山には強制的なものだけを置くことができます
Many volcanoes in Japan are used as a reference
日本の多くの火山が参考にされています
But I must say that this reference is really just for reference
しかし、この参考資料はあくまで参考であると言わざるを得ません。
cannot...
できません...
much is still unknown
多くはまだ知られていない
It is very difficult, because many people and most of the civil government have been asking about this matter
多くの人々とほとんどの政府がこの問題について疑問を抱いているので、これは非常に難しいことです。
this needs to be worked on
これは取り組む必要がある
the lady
女性
Mr. Lin, I would like to ask you for advice, because I often take Chinese and foreign tourists to small tourists
林さん、私は中国人や外国人観光客を小さな観光客に連れて行くことが多いので、アドバイスをお願いします。
I remember that there was a magnitude 5.5 earthquake about half a year ago this year
今年半年ほど前にマグニチュード5.5の地震があったと記憶しています。
very close to taipei
台北にとても近い
In a few days, I will take tourists to Xiaoyoukeng
数日中に観光客を小油坑に連れて行きます
I just realized I haven't gone yet
まだ行ってないことに今気づきました
I'm going to the parking lot
駐車場に行きます
I heard a loud noise like a jet plane
ジェット機のような大きな音が聞こえた
i never heard
聞いたことがない
wow you're the first to hear
わあ、あなたが初めて聞きました
I always
私はいつも
the airport is very big
空港はとても大きいです
Because I often take Chinese and foreign tourists to that scenic spot
私はよく中国人や外国人観光客をその景勝地に連れて行きますので
I've never heard of such a big
そんな大きな話は聞いたことがない
as big as a jet plane right next to your ear
ジェット機ほどの大きさが耳のすぐそばにある
I was thinking then
その時私は考えていました
My video should start leading everyone away
私のビデオがみんなを遠ざけ始めるはずです
escape with everyone
みんなで逃げる
But two months later
しかし2ヶ月後
when i go
僕が行く時
that voice is gone
その声は消えた
Then you often monitor over there
それからあなたはよくあそこを監視します
i don't know
わからない
This is a very common phenomenon
これは非常に一般的な現象です
it's just that loud
それだけうるさいです
The sound of that jet is different from what I usually go to
そのジェットの音はいつも行くところとは違う
The other one is that the information I read is that
もう一つは、私が読んだ情報は、
Are the two judgments
二つの判決ですか
Volcano
火火山
one that you just listed
あなたが今リストしたもの
All I've read is that
私が読んだのはそれだけです
two hundred thousand years
二十万年
The first condition is two hundred thousand years
最初の条件は20万年です
The second condition is
2つ目の条件は、
Is there a magma chamber
マグマだまりはあるのか
Then I know that the magma chamber
そうするとマグマだまりがあることが分かりました
we now know there is
私たちは今、存在することを知っています
So we used to define it as repairing volcanoes
そこで私たちはこれを火山の修復と定義していました
or even a stone volcano
あるいは石の火山でも
Should be changed now, yes
今すぐ変更する必要があります、はい
Then I also read about Guishan Island
それから亀山島についても読みました。
The last eruption seems to be 200,000 years ago, isn't it?
最後の噴火は20万年前のようですね。
four times
四回
then i want to know
それから私は知りたいです
I compare the correct dating method
正しいデート方法を比較してみます
i should say
言うべきだ
which one should be used
どちらを使用すべきか
Which one was the last eruption?
最後に噴火したのはどれですか?
Because I obviously 200,000 is out of the question
明らかに20万は論外だから
200,000 is not
20万ではない
ten thousand years
一万年
Ten thousand years is actually related to the central
一万年は実は中央と関係がある
the Geological Survey
地質調査所
active fault
活断層
That is, the most active active fault is 10,000 years old.
つまり、最も活発な活断層は1万年前のものです。
So ten thousand years is them
それで一万年ですか
In the geological world, they are equivalent to having a
地質学の世界では、それらは
As long as it is a living geological thing
生きた地質物である限り
regardless of volcanic faults
火山断層とは関係なく
10,000 is used as a reference
10,000 を基準として使用します
200,000 is too long
20万は長すぎる
200,000 that carbon
200,000 そのカーボン
and you just heard me really
そしてあなたは今私の話を本当に聞いてくれました
also hope that
それも願っています
if you can take your time
お時間をいただければ
probably tell me
おそらく教えてください
Because we now have a 24 hour record
24時間の記録が残っているので
That
それか
If you probably have, how often do you say
おそらくそうしている場合、どれくらいの頻度で言いますか
In my impression, I watched it carefully for half a year
半年じっくり観た感想としては
I spent a lot of time carefully
時間をかけて丁寧に作りました
Just 20 hours of constant inspection
わずか 20 時間の常時検査
About 10 days on average
平均10日程度
two weeks
二週間
Anyway, about 10 days or so
とりあえず10日くらいかな
I can probably add to the sound of this so-called place name
このいわゆる地名の響きに付け加えてもいいかもしれない
But sometimes very often
でも時々とても頻繁に
Sometimes it's 3 days
3日の場合もあります
always have
いつももっている
sometimes sporadically
時々散発的に
Just once or twice a week
週に1、2回だけ
so if you can really hear
それで本当に聞こえるなら
Because I often ask people
人によく聞くので
Because of my information, I see that there is really
私の情報のおかげで、本当に存在することが分かりました
but i didn't really hear anyone
でも本当に誰にも聞こえなかった
So you probably have this very precious
だからあなたはおそらくこれを非常に貴重なものを持っているでしょう
is that I believe he usually looks like
彼は普段次のように見えると思います
just pissed off
ただ怒っているだけ
But sporadically there will be something like
しかし、散発的に次のようなことがあります
like firecrackers
爆竹のように
loud this
大声でこれ
exploded
爆発した
Otherwise, I can't receive the earthquake
そうしないと地震が受信できない
like an ice cream machine
アイスクリームマシンのように
that should be
そうあるべきだ
What you describe is that it is relatively low frequency
あなたが説明しているのは、比較的低い周波数であるということです
then a little longer
それからもう少し
very double
とても二重
Yeah
うん
and heavy
そして重い
wow this is very
うわー、これはとても
yes
はい
volcanic words
火山の言葉
fire volcano it is very common words
火の火山、それは非常に一般的な言葉です
can there be a way
方法はありますか
can make it a stone volcano
石の火山にすることもできる
Is it right
そうですか
because it is said to be in the volcano
火山の中にあると言われているので
while it's working
それが働いている間
we invest something in
私たちは何かに投資します
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
then to destroy it
それからそれを破壊するために
reduce it fire volcano regulations
火火山規制を減らす
this is feasible
これは実現可能です
but is it possible to do
でもそれは可能ですか？
this
これ
this is a bit difficult
これは少し難しいです
like an earthquake some people say
地震のように言う人もいる
shock energy failed
ショックエネルギーが失敗しました
So this fault
それでこの欠点は
he just wanted to say
彼はただ言いたかっただけです
we just let it
私たちはただそれをそのままにします
small earthquake
小地震
A big earthquake turns into many small earthquakes
大きな地震が起こると、小さな地震がたくさん起こります。
we water it
私たちはそれに水をやります
this is science
これは科学です
fault
障害
you pump it in
あなたはそれをポンプで送り込みます
it will start to slide and release energy
滑り始めてエネルギーを放出します
But this is very risky, no one dares to do it, why?
しかし、これは非常に危険です、誰もそれをしようとしません、なぜですか？
Yes, usually it is fine, if you add water to it, it will cause a big earthquake, who will be responsible
はい、普通は大丈夫です、水を入れると大地震が起きます、誰が責任をとりますか
In fact, you can't control it's potion, it's still potion
実際、あなたはそれを制御することはできません、それはポーションです、それはまだポーションです
The same problem, that is, the natural world of volcanoes, I think it may be difficult for us
同じ問題、つまり火山という自然界でも、私たちには難しいかもしれないと思います
With current technology it is possible
現在の技術ではそれが可能です
Because the magma chamber is over there.
あそこにマグマだまりがあるから。
It should be said that it is possible, but I don't know how to do it now
それは可能であると言うべきですが、今それを行う方法がわかりません
Yes
はい
You just mentioned that Yellowstone is a giant volcano
先ほどイエローストーンは巨大な火山だと言いましたね
How is the so-called super large, medium or small volcano defined?
いわゆる超大・中・小火山とはどのように定義されるのでしょうか？
So how dangerous is it?
それで、それはどれくらい危険ですか？
Probably it is easy for us to define it now, just look at the magma household
おそらく、今ではそれを定義するのは簡単でしょう。マグマの世帯を見てください。
Like this volume of the magma house
マグマハウスのこの巻のように
Like the one in Yellowstone Park, maybe
イエローストーン公園のようなものかもしれません
Seems like thousands of cubic kilometers
数千立方キロメートルに見える
A few thousand, not like fifteen thousand or so
1万5千とかではなく、数千
It just looks like our big round volcano may only be
私たちの大きな丸い火山は、ただ存在するだけのようです。
Only a hundred, about a hundred Cheng Qi
チェン・チーはわずか百、約百人
Of course, the bigger the magma household
もちろん、マグマ世帯が大きいほど、
It only takes a little bit of it to be quite impressive
ほんの少しだけでもかなり印象的なものになります
If the magma household is small
マグマ世帯が小さい場合
Of course it is less dangerous
もちろん危険も少ないです
So volcanoes are graded
火山には等級が付けられている
It is divided into one, two, three, four, and five grades according to the magma
マグマの種類により1級、2級、3級、4級、5級に分けられます。
many graded
多くのグレード
there is a child
子供がいます
Just now I saw a few after the volcanic eruption
たった今、火山の噴火後にいくつか見ました
Residents have examples of fleeing
住民には逃亡例がある
Then I want to ask that after the volcano ceases to be active
そこで聞きたいのは、火山の活動が終わった後についてです。
How soon can they go back and live there
彼らはどれくらい早く戻ってそこに住むことができますか
wow, this is another problem
うわー、これはまた別の問題です
In fact, the volcano told people to evacuate
実際、火山は人々に避難するよう呼びかけました
relatively easy
比較的簡単な
and then after evacuation
そして避難後
when can we let people go back
いつになったら人々を戻せるのか
People in general always want to go back
一般の人はいつも戻りたいと思っています
it looks like as long as it doesn't smoke
煙を出さない限りはそう見える
he just wants to go back
彼はただ戻りたいだけです
But the role unit, the government, is actually very difficult
しかし、役割単位である政府は実際には非常に難しいです
because just said
たった今言ったから
when people go up
人が登るとき
We can easily see those steps
それらのステップを簡単に確認できます
But he scurried to a certain word
しかし彼はある言葉に急いだ
Then start writing...
それから書き始めます...
when there is no change
変化がないとき
When will it suddenly rise again
いつになったらまた一気に上がるんだろう
In fact, the politics started to be very blurred
実際、政治は非常に曖昧になり始めた
even say when it will start to be quiet
いつ静かになり始めるかさえ言う
no good reference
良い参考になりません
sometimes in absolute units
時には絶対単位で
it's just a decision
それは単なる決断です
So going back is actually a big trouble
だから戻るのは実際には大きな問題だ
when can we go back
いつ戻れますか
like hawaii, right?
ハワイみたいですよね？
move at midnight
真夜中に移動する
then it seems to stop
そしたら止まりそうです
recently again
最近またまた
like that paris island
あのパリ島のように
Last October was like two months of activity
昨年の 10 月は 2 か月ほどの活動でした
Then it stops in the middle
そうすると途中で止まってしまいます
That July the last July
あの7月 去年の7月
Paris Island is back in action
パリ島が活動を再開
So when it starts moving
だからそれが動き始めると
That kind of estimation is actually more difficult.
この種の推定は実際にはさらに困難です。
But from being quiet to moving
しかし、静かな状態から動く状態へ
It's actually easier
実際はもっと簡単です
from motion to silence
動から静へ
that is
あれは
not so easy
そう簡単ではない
so still need a lot
まだたくさん必要なので
lady behind
後ろの女性
I just want to ask
ただ聞きたいのですが
that researcher is
その研究者は
Because I told you a long time ago
ずっと前に言ったから
Earthquakes can be predicted with animals
動物で地震を予知できる
like a fish or a snake or something
魚か蛇か何かのように
But have you ever thought about using animals?
しかし、動物を利用することを考えたことはありますか?
I don't know it's probably not practical either
それもおそらく実用的ではないかはわかりません
but maybe there is a way
でも、もしかしたら方法があるかもしれない
Have you ever been through this period?
この時期を経験したことがありますか？
still have you thought about it
まだ考えていますか
this is good
これはいい
It's the earthquake why we use animals
動物を使う理由は地震だから
in what strange way
何という奇妙な方法で
Because the science of earthquake prediction
地震予知の科学だから
At the scientific level, everyone feels that it is not feasible yet.
科学レベルでは、まだ実現可能ではないと誰もが感じています。
So everyone is that if you go to a western doctor
それで、西洋の医者に行くなら、誰もがそう思います
I found out that you are terminally ill and cannot be cured.
あなたが末期の病気で、治すことができないことがわかりました。
Then everyone finds a way, right?
そうすれば、誰もが方法を見つけますよね？
But in terms of volcanoes
しかし、火山に関して言えば、
He tells you about science
彼は科学について教えてくれます
If the volcano wants a prescription
火山が処方箋を必要とするなら
there is a lot of evidence
たくさんの証拠があります
Why should I look for a remedy?
なぜ治療法を探す必要があるのでしょうか?
So in terms of volcanoes
火山の言葉で言えば
You do these monitoring for formal evidence
正式な証拠のためにこれらのモニタリングを行います
probably the answer
おそらく答え
But the earthquake is still touching
しかし、地震はまだ続いています
Thousands of dollars and ideas will come out
数千ドルとアイデアが出てくるでしょう
Thanks
ありがとう
I want to confirm one thing with your professor
教授に一つ確認したいことがあります
months ago
数か月前
There was an earthquake at more than four o'clock in Beitou
北投で4時過ぎに地震がありました
Exactly the same result when I saw
見たときと全く同じ結果でした
It seems to be near Zhongshan Building
中山ビルの近くにあるようです
That's very close to the volcanoes in the big picture
それは全体的に見ると火山に非常に近いです
Later, the Meteorological Bureau said that it was due to the movement of the plate.
その後、気象庁はプレートの移動によるものだと発表した。
but i doubt it
しかし私はそれを疑います
so according to your opinion
だからあなたの意見によれば
The earthquake caused by the same thing
同じ事で起きた地震
Is it really a plate movement?
それは本当にプレートの動きですか？
Or a shock from the volcanoes
それとも火山の衝撃か
if i remember correctly
もし私が正確に覚えていれば
you may be asking to have a
を求めているかもしれません
They called it the Beitou Earthquake at first
最初は北投地震と呼ばれていました
It's about five o'clock
5時くらいです
Because for many years Taipei City has not
なぜなら、台北市は長年にわたって
the same earthquake that happened
同じ地震が起きた
The earthquake was actually reported by the Meteorological Bureau.
実際にこの地震は気象庁から報告されました。
There should be nothing wrong, the reason is that the earthquake was more than 100 kilometers deep
何も問題はないはずです。その理由は、地震の深さが100キロメートル以上だったからです。
So that is the earthquake of the plate that is on the screen with our Philippine Sea plate going north.
これは、フィリピン海プレートが北上しているときに画面に表示されているプレートの地震です。
It's not on the very shallow surface of the volcano this 10 kilometers
この10キロメートルの火山の非常に浅い表面にはありません
If it's at 5km 10km it's more to do with volcanoes
5km、10kmの場合は火山と関係があります。
But is it 140 or what? 140 kilometers, it is very deep, and it has something to do with the plate
でも、それは 140 キロですか? 140 キロメートル、それは非常に深いです、そしてそれはプレートと関係があります
So this explanation from the Meteorological Bureau is basically OK.
ですから、この気象庁の説明は基本的にはＯＫです。
It is accepted by science
それは科学によって認められています
hello mr behind
こんにちは、後ろのミスター
Hello, Mr. Lin, what I want to ask is, as far as we know, the threat of volcanoes in northern Taiwan
こんにちは、リンさん。私が聞きたいのは、私たちが知る限り、台湾北部の火山の脅威についてです。
In addition to the Big Butt Volcano, the undersea volcano in Keelung is also a volcanic volcano
大尻火山に加えて、基隆の海底火山も火山です。
And it may have been active in Keelung Sea School in 1867
そして1867年には基隆海洋学校で活動していた可能性があります
In the future, will we target such
将来的にはそのようなこともターゲットにするのでしょうか？
Disaster risk will do some scientific research
災害リスクは科学的研究を行う
Thanks
ありがとう
Yes, I'm personally very interested
はい、個人的にとても興味があります
You are actually many, many professional
あなたは本当にたくさんのプロフェッショナルです
It is because of Keelung Port
基隆港のせいです
that
それか
Below Zheng there is a seabed and there is a volcano
鄭の下には海底と火山がある
submarine volcano
海底火山
And they do ocean exploration
そして彼らは海洋探査を行っています
That volcano will still have majestic
あの火山はまだ雄大なままだろう
It means it's a volcano
つまり火山です
That teacher Xi Zhiwen from CUHK
中華人民共和国のあの習志文先生
And that National Taiwan University teacher Yang Shanghai
そしてあの国立台湾大学の楊上海先生
they just do some research
彼らはただ研究をしているだけです
Then I also believe
それなら私も信じます
I personally believe
私は個人的に信じています
this has to be confirmed
これは確認する必要があります
It was the tsunami in 1867
それは1867年の津波でした
Probably
おそらく
Because it was said earlier that the tsunami caused by the earthquake
先ほど、地震による津波があったとのことでしたので、
but the volcano
しかし火山
Tsunamis caused by submarine volcanic activity
海底火山活動による津波
In fact, the possibility is quite high
実はその可能性はかなり高い
but need evidence
でも証拠が必要だ
that we need to investigate
調査する必要があること
So this piece of the future
だからこの未来の部分は
the government does too
政府もそうする
I personally would
私は個人的にそうするだろう
will be very involved in doing it
それに大いに関与するだろう
It's just that the investigation and research in the sea is more difficult
ただ海での調査・研究はより困難です
so we need
だから私たちには必要です
more of these techniques
これらのテクニックをもっと見る
or some way to
または何らかの方法で
It's hard work I'm worth doing
大変な仕事だけどやる価値がある
yes
はい
Hello teacher, those two questions
こんにちは、先生、その 2 つの質問です
The first question is about the prediction of volcanic eruptions
第一問目は火山噴火の予知についてです。
It's what you just mentioned
それはあなたが今言ったことです
If you try to predict a volcanic eruption
火山の噴火を予測しようとすると
We can see that it was before the earthquake
地震前だったことがわかります
It is possible to slowly change forward from a relatively deep place
比較的深い場所からゆっくりと前方にチェンジすることが可能
Then but what I want to ask is
それで、でも聞きたいのは、
The speed at which the magma is extruded from the ground
マグマが地面から押し出される速度
how fast it can
どれくらい早くできるか
If a whole bunch of predictions today happen within two hours
今日の大量の予測が 2 時間以内に起こるとしたら
Like what kind of hot spring water becomes hot?
どのような温泉水が熱くなりますか？
or place names
地名とか
just too helpless
無力すぎる
could it be in two hours
2時間以内でしょうか
maybe or within an hour
たぶん、あるいは1時間以内に
It's all ordinary earthquakes
全部普通の地震だよ
Then the water temperature of the hot springs and the like
それから温泉の湯温など
Is it possible to have such a fast speed
そんなに速いスピードが出せるのか
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
Excuse me
すみません
Then the second question is
それでは2番目の質問は、
about that fire pot
あの火鍋のこと
that's me in the magazine
雑誌に載っているのは私です
That is, there are three crater lakes in Africa.
つまり、アフリカには火口湖が3つあるということです。
Then what used to happen was
それから、かつて何が起こっていたかというと、
It's the volcano under the crater lake.
火口湖の下にある火山です。
It's the gas that erupts and causes
噴出して原因となるのはガスです
carbon dioxide in the lake
湖の中の二酸化炭素
What concentration is saturated or something like that?
飽和する濃度などは何ですか？
And then this carbon dioxide floats out of this lake
そしてこの二酸化炭素がこの湖から漂ってきます
and killed an entire village in one night
そして一晩で村全体を殺した
Then what I want to ask is
そこで聞きたいのは、
Is it possible for this to happen in Taiwan?
台湾でもこんな事が起きる可能性はあるのでしょうか？
because we just heard
ちょうど聞いたばかりなので
That is, Taiwan has submarine volcanoes.
つまり、台湾には海底火山があるのです。
There are many hot springs I don't know
知らない温泉がたくさんある
Is it because Taiwan has this condition that this kind of thing will happen?
台湾がこのような条件を備えているから、このようなことが起こるのでしょうか？
that's it thank you
それはそれで、ありがとう
The first question is to say
最初の質問はこう言います
will it be one hour two hours
1時間2時間になりますか
Suddenly the volcano erupts
突然火山が噴火した
basically it should be hard
基本的には難しいはずです
Because the magma actually moves its body
マグマは実際に体を動かすので
It's actually very sticky
実はすごく粘着質なのです
it won't be like a bomb
爆弾のようなものではないだろう
Run from 5 kilometers to 10 kilometers to the surface in one go
地上まで5キロから10キロを一気に走る
can't be that fast
そんなに速くはできない
usually a few weeks
通常は数週間
months or even years
何か月、あるいは何年も
it pants slowly
ゆっくり喘ぐ
So within a short period of time
それで短期間のうちに
It should be theoretically not
理論的にはそうではないはずです
about crater lake
火口湖について
Actually that's because
実はそれは、
It's a volcano full of camps
キャンプがいっぱいの火山です
there is a crater
クレーターがある
like a lake
湖のように
Then there will be a lot of water
そうすると水がたくさん出てきます
that volcanic gas
あの火山ガス
In fact, a lot of acid
実は酸が多い
And CO2 is the most
そしてCO2が一番多い
There is also a lot of acid
酸もたっぷりです
So these can easily become sour
なので酸っぱくなりやすいです
carbonic acid
炭酸
Of course for plant organisms
もちろん植物にも
Or animals actually have a lot of influence
それとも動物が実際に大きな影響力を持っているのか
so you just have to be in crater lake
だからあなたはクレーター湖にいればいいのです
if there is volcanic activity
火山活動がある場合
In fact, the water will become very acidic.
実際、水は非常に酸性になります。
will affect
影響するだろう
But under the sea
でも海の下では
This problem may be less
この問題は少なくなるかもしれません
Because the sea is water after all, it is big
海はやっぱり水だから大きいですね
so it will be diluted
だから薄まるだろう
but
しかし
There is little water in the lake
湖には水が少ない
So it will be relatively high concentration
なので比較的高濃度になります
will be more harmful
より有害になるだろう
The sea area probably
おそらく海域
Unless it happens to be in an undersea crater
たまたま海底クレーターでない限り
Creatures there may be affected
そこにいる生き物が影響を受ける可能性があります
But it's easy to dilute
でも薄めるのは簡単
There's another one here
ここにもう一つあります
Hello teacher
こんにちは先生
What about Datong Volcano?
大同火山はどうですか？
Our year with the Giant Volcano Society is
私たちの巨大火山協会との年は、
The last climb was within a few thousand years
最後の登頂は数千年以内だった
then ask the teacher
それから先生に聞いてください
The year of the Volcano Society is
火山学会の年は
probably what kind of method
おそらくどのような方法でしょうか
may the teacher explain
先生が説明してくださいますか
volcano will it actually be
火山は本当にそうなるのだろうか
There are many of them are simple to use
使い方が簡単なものがたくさんあります
carbon fourteen
カーボン14
some of its half lives
その半生の一部
So many address fields use
非常に多くの住所フィールドで使用されている
use half-life
半減期を使う
then it is a
それならそれは
a decay it takes
衰退が必要
how many years then see if it is
何年後、それがあるかどうかを確認してください
The ratio is attenuated several times
比率は数倍に減衰します
then how many years
それから何年
It's probably like this for many years
たぶん何年もこんな感じ
that's the place to use that half-life
そこがその半減期を活かす場所だ
The half-life of course
半減期は当然
Carbon stone is often used for thousands of years to ten thousand years
炭素石は数千年から一万年にわたって使用されることが多い
But if it's hundreds of thousands of years or millions
でもそれが何十万年か何百万年だったら
It has another life-releasing business that it can do
生命を解放するためにできるもう一つのビジネスがある
Make nails or teeth
爪や歯を作る
So they have professionals who are doing this
彼らにはこれを行う専門家がいます
yes
はい
Do you have
ありますか
well here is the last one
さて、これが最後です
last question
最後一個問題
I just want to ask
ただ聞きたいのですが
that pyroclastic
あの火砕流
Can you predict the direction
方向を予測できますか
because at that time
なぜならその時は
Pompeii will be submerged by pyroclastic flow
ポンペイが火砕流で水没する
That is, it goes in that direction
つまり、その方向に進むということです
And then there's another
そして、もう一つあります
neapolitan place
ナポリの場所
if it's like taipei
台北みたいだったら
Words distributed by Datong Volcano
大同火山が配布した言葉
can we just be
そのままでいいですか
predict which direction it will go
どの方向に進むかを予測する
Then we can avoid that disaster
そうすれば、私たちはその災害を避けることができます
yes
はい
the answer is yes
答えははいです
It's as simple as water
それは水と同じくらい簡単です
you pour the water down
あなたは水を注ぎます
it goes to the lowest flow
それは一番低い流れに行きます
In fact, for this, like Japan, especially Japan, a lot of work has been done.
実際、このために、日本と同様、特に日本では多くの取り組みが行われてきました。
For example, he looked at the village, that, that, the ancient ground is the village
たとえば、彼は村を見て、あれ、あの、古代の土地、それは村でした。
then what do they do
それで彼らは何をしますか
The taxes flowed down and rushed to the village
税金が流れ落ちて村に押し寄せた
They make something like this gutter or retaining wall
この側溝や擁壁のようなものを作ります。
It’s a bit like the concept of flood control, which is to be a very, very resolute body.
それは治水の概念に似ており、非常に毅然とした組織でなければなりません。
When the tax flow comes to meet that body, he will turn the corner
税の流れがその体に会う時、彼は角を曲がるだろう
won't rush to the village
急いで村に行かないだろう
So this can be predicted and pre-cast.
したがって、これは予測して事前にキャストすることができます。
Then make some preparations for evacuation
それから避難の準備をしましょう
So Japan has done a lot in this regard
この点に関して日本は多くのことを行ってきた
yes
はい
good
良い
it's almost time
もうすぐです
i want to end
終わりたい
uh bring back the preview
ああ、プレビューを戻して
Our feast of knowledge next month in August
来月8月の知識の饗宴
by Chen Zhicheng
陳志成著
Institute of Biomedical Sciences
生物医科学研究所
What's the matter with soreness?
痛みはどうしたの？
So this is a life science subject
これは生命科学の科目です
Let's Talk Slowly
ゆっくり話しましょう
Human figure and acid receptor molecule
人体と酸受容体分子
before all of us are ready to leave
私たち全員が出発する準備が整う前に
Let's give another round of applause
もう一度拍手を送りましょう
Thank you for the wonderful speech today
今日は素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
good
良い
Thank you all for coming
お越しいただきありがとうございました